[{"key":1,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"sports","question":"Who was the first medallist at the modern Olympics?","a":"James B.Connolly","b":"Jim Thorpe","c":"Raymond Ewry","d":"Norman Pritchard"},{"key":2,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"sports","question":"Who was the first bowler to achieve a hatrick in test cricket?","a":"Willy Bates","b":"Johny Briggs","c":"Fred Spofforth","d":"George Lohman"},{"key":3,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"sports","question":"Which team did the Indian hockey team defeat,by a margin of 24-1 in the 1932 Olympics?","a":"Australia","b":"Pakistan","c":"Korea","d":"U S A"},{"key":4,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"sports","question":"What is the maximum no of goals scored in the finals of a football world cup?","a":"Seven","b":"Nine","c":"Six","d":"Eight"},{"key":5,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"sports","question":"What was the name of the mascot for the 1998 world soccer cup?","a":"Januars","b":"April","c":"Jules","d":"Junes"},{"key":6,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"sports","question":"Where was the first foot ball world cup held?","a":"Paraguay","b":"Uruguay","c":"Brazil","d":"Argentina"},{"key":7,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"sports","question":"How many test centuries has Sir.Don Bradman scored?","a":"Twenty six","b":"Twenty Nine","c":"Thirty","d":"Thirty three"},{"key":8,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"sports","question":"How many runs did Sachin Tendulkar score in his first one day international cricket match?","a":"117","b":"99","c":"0","d":"53"},{"key":9,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"sports","question":"Who has scored the maximum number of centuries in ODI?","a":"Allan Border","b":"Sachin Tendulkar","c":"Vivian Richards","d":"Mark Waugh"},{"key":10,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"sports","question":"Which one of the following games has never been included in a single Olympics?","a":"Cricket","b":"Croquet","c":"Lacrosse","d":"Formula - 1"},{"key":11,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"sports","question":"The first Asian cup games were held in 1956. When was the cup system introduced?","a":"1972","b":"1956","c":"1960","d":"1996"},{"key":12,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"sports","question":"Where are the 2004 Olympics going to be held?","a":"Seoul","b":"Barcelona","c":"Montreal","d":"Athens"},{"key":13,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"sports","question":"What was Don Bradman's score in his last innings?","a":"273","b":"0","c":"199","d":"99"},{"key":14,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"sports","question":"When was the first marathon for women introduced?","a":"1984","b":"b","c":" Munich","d":"1976"},{"key":15,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"sports","question":"Which sprinter is called 'Lion Queen' ?","a":"Marion Jones","b":"P.T.Usha","c":"Merlene Ottey","d":"Florence Griffith Joyner"},{"key":16,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"sports","question":"Which tournament was played in the Longwoods Cricket Club?","a":"Davis cup","b":"Euro 2000 Soccer cup","c":"Benson & Hedges cup","d":"Asian games"},{"key":17,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"sports","question":"The Dronacharya awards are given for excellence in which field?","a":"Coaching","b":"Selection","c":"Managing","d":"Defence"},{"key":18,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"sports","question":"Who was the first Indian to score a hatrick in foot ball at the Olympic games?","a":"Baichung Bhutia","b":"Jamu sepoy","c":"Neville de Souza","d":"Rajeev Sinha"},{"key":19,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"sports","question":"Who was the 1st person to be judged runout through a T.V replay?","a":"Sachin Tendulkar","b":"Martin Crowe","c":"Javed Mianded","d":"Hansie Cronje"},{"key":20,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"sports","question":"Kiren Bedi has represented India in which sport?","a":"Cricket","b":"100m Sprint","c":"High Jump","d":"Tennis"},{"key":21,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"sports","question":"In NBA , if the Bulls are from Chicago, where are the Rockheads from?","a":"Indiana","b":"New York","c":"Washington","d":"Housten"},{"key":22,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"sports","question":"Where were the first Winter Olympics held?","a":"St.Moritz","b":"b","c":"USA","d":"Oslo"},{"key":23,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"sports","question":"Who was the first Indian woman to swim across the English Channel?","a":"Steffi Sequira","b":"Aarti Saha","c":"Elizebeth Davenport","d":"Leela Rao"},{"key":24,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"sports","question":"What is the real name of champion golfer Tiger woods?","a":"Frederick","b":"Ferdinand","c":"Sam","d":"Eldick"},{"key":25,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"sports","question":"Which hockey star's autobiography was titled 'GOALS'","a":"Dhyan Chand","b":"Roop Chand","c":"Vace Paes","d":"Bhaskaran"},{"key":26,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"sports","question":"With how many red balls is Snooker played?","a":"Ten","b":"Twelve","c":"Fifteen","d":"Seventeen"},{"key":27,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"sports","question":"Who was the first woman Tennis player to win a golden slam?","a":"Martina Hingis","b":"Conchita Martinez","c":"Steffi Graf","d":"Monica Seles"},{"key":28,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"sports","question":"Which is the only other living object, allowed to take part in Olympics, besides humans?","a":"Dove","b":"Horse","c":"Bull","d":"Ostrich"},{"key":29,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"sports","question":"Which team was the first runner up in Cricket World Cup?","a":"England","b":"New zealand","c":"South Africa","d":"Australia"},{"key":30,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"sports","question":"With which sport would you associate Bill Tilden?","a":"Tennis","b":"Cricket","c":"Badminton","d":"Polo"},{"key":31,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"sports","question":"In 1932 at LA, India beat USA  with a margin of 23 goals . Who scored the maximum ","a":"Dhyan Chand","b":"Roop Singh","c":"Vace Paes","d":"Bhaskaran"},{"key":32,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"sports","question":"Who was the first gymnast to score a 'Perfect Ten'?","a":"Nadia Comaneci","b":"Paaro Nurmi","c":"Lasse Viren","d":"Jim Thorpe"},{"key":33,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"sports","question":"Where were the 1995 S A F games held?","a":"Karachi","b":"New Delhi","c":"Dhaka","d":"Chennai"},{"key":34,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"sports","question":"Who was the first Australian player to be knighted?","a":"Tod Woodbridge","b":"Don Bradman","c":"Peter Rasmusan","d":"Daniel Ezpore"},{"key":35,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"sports","question":"Where is the Salt Lake stadium situated ?","a":"USA","b":"b","c":" Sydney","d":"India"},{"key":36,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"sports","question":"In which sport would you come across the term 'Chinaman'?","a":"Badminton","b":"Table Tennis","c":"Cricket","d":"Polo"},{"key":37,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"sports","question":"What was the name of the first tennis club?","a":"Wellington club","b":"Limington club","c":"Pallota club","d":"Gustava club"},{"key":38,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"sports","question":"Who was the only West Indian in Sir Don Bradman's dream team?","a":"Vivian Richards","b":"Clive Lloyd","c":"Courtney Walsh","d":"Gary Sobers"},{"key":39,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"sports","question":"The Hopman Cup' and the' Porsche Grand Prix' are tournaments associated with which sport?","a":"Formula-1","b":"Tennis","c":"Badminton","d":"Equistrian"},{"key":40,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"sports","question":"In which Olympics did India first win 2 medals?","a":"1900","b":"b","c":"Los Angeles","d":"1952"},{"key":41,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"sports","question":"Besides cricket,in which other sport would one play a Test series?","a":"Foot ball","b":"Formula-1","c":"Hockey","d":"Sumo wrestling"},{"key":42,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"sports","question":"Which spinner bowled Don Bradman for a duck in his last match?","a":"Jim Laker","b":"Eric Hollies","c":"Thomas James Matthews","d":"Hugh Trumble"},{"key":43,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"sports","question":"Chess Champion Vishwanathan Anand was domiciled in which country?","a":"France","b":"Italy","c":"Spain","d":"England"},{"key":44,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"sports","question":"Which cricketer is known as Guy , the Gorilla?","a":"Henry Olongo","b":"Pummellelo Mbwanga","c":"Geoffrey Boycott","d":"Ian Botham"},{"key":45,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"sports","question":"When did Vishwanathan Anand become India's first grandmaster?","a":"1994","b":"1985","c":"1987","d":"1990"},{"key":46,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"sports","question":"In which game would one come across the term, Short Run?","a":"Cricket","b":"Base ball","c":"Squash","d":"Polo"},{"key":47,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"sports","question":"Who was the first head of the FIFA?","a":"D.B.Wickfall","b":"Robert Goverin","c":"Jules Rimet","d":"Sap Blatter"},{"key":48,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"sports","question":"Who was the first Indian to win the 'All England Badminton Championship'?","a":"Naresh Natekar","b":"Pullela Gopichand","c":"Amrit Diwan","d":"Prakash Padukone"},{"key":49,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"sports","question":"Which game is played in the Tumbukhum Stadium?","a":"Cricket","b":"Hockey","c":"Rugby","d":"Indoor games"},{"key":50,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"sports","question":"Who was the first Cricketer to score a 300 in Test matches?","a":"Warren Bardsley","b":"Don Bradman","c":"Andy Sandham","d":"Charles Bannerman"},{"key":51,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"sports","question":"In which country was the word'Test Match' first used?","a":"Australia","b":"England","c":"West Indies","d":"East Africa"},{"key":52,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"sports","question":"Where did India play its first Test match?","a":"Melbourne","b":"Oval","c":"Kingston","d":"Lords"},{"key":53,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"sports","question":"Which England cricket captain was also an Olympic boxing champion?","a":"Graham Gooch","b":"J.W.H.T.Douglas","c":"Maurice Tate","d":"W.Gunn"},{"key":54,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"sports","question":"How many Australian open titles has Bjorn Borg won?","a":"None","b":"One","c":"Two","d":"Five"},{"key":55,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"sports","question":"Which is the highest national sports award in India?","a":"Arjuna award","b":"Dronacharya awards","c":"Rajiv Gandhi khel Ratna","d":"Chakra Khel awards"},{"key":56,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"sports","question":"With which sport would you associate Kennath Bosen?","a":"Boxing","b":"Weight Lifting","c":"Golf","d":"Athletics"},{"key":57,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"sports","question":"Who was adjudged Man of the Match in the 1983 cricket world cup finals?","a":"Kapil Dev","b":"Chetan Sharma","c":"Roger Binny","d":"Mohinder Amarnath"},{"key":58,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"sports","question":"Which Cricketer is known as Ice man?","a":"Steve Waugh","b":"Rahul Dravid","c":"Shiv Narine Chanderpaul","d":"Nasser Hussain"},{"key":59,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"sports","question":"Who is called Beefy?","a":"Sachin Tendulkar","b":"Ian Botham","c":"Inzamam -Ul-Haq","d":"David Sheperd"},{"key":60,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"sports","question":"What is 26 miles and 385 yards long?","a":"longest hight jump rod","b":"max. distance in discuss","c":"max dist.in a hammer throw","d":"A marathon race"},{"key":61,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"sports","question":"With which sport would you associate the ELO ratings?","a":"Soccer","b":"Chess","c":"Badminton","d":"Tennis"},{"key":62,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"sports","question":"Where was the first test match played in Pakistan?","a":"Ahmed Nager","b":"Karachi","c":"Dhaka","d":"Amritsar"},{"key":63,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"sports","question":"Who was the oldest gold medalist in the Olympics games?","a":"Oscar Swahn","b":"J.Connolly","c":"Sidney Hinds","d":"Dick Button"},{"key":64,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"sports","question":"When did India achieve its first success in Basket Ball?","a":"1982","b":"1962","c":"1932","d":"1952"},{"key":65,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"sports","question":"What is the record for highest score in a basket ball match?","a":"176-42","b":"220-143","c":"192-56","d":"251-33"},{"key":66,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"sports","question":"Which country won the most golds in the first Olympics?","a":"USA","b":"Greece","c":"Britain","d":"France"},{"key":67,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"sports","question":"Which Olympics were called Phantom Games?","a":"1902","b":"1900","c":"1906","d":"1910"},{"key":68,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"sports","question":"Who was the captain of the Australian cricket team when it first won the world cup in 1987?","a":"Steve Waugh","b":"Allan Border","c":"Andrew Hilditch","d":"Robin Smith"},{"key":69,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"sports","question":"Who was the first bowler to take 10 wickets in a single test innings?","a":"Jim laker","b":"Anil Kumble","c":"SF Barnes","d":"J.Briggs"},{"key":70,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"sports","question":"What was foot ball great Pele's jersey number?","a":"24","b":"100","c":"7","d":"10"},{"key":71,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"sports","question":"Which famous foot baller is acredited with the 'Hand of God' goal?","a":"Pele","b":"D.Maradona","c":"Ronaldo","d":"Michael Owen"},{"key":72,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"sports","question":"When and where were the first Common wealth games held?","a":"1934","b":"b","c":" Sydney","d":"1930"},{"key":73,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"sports","question":"Who was the first Indian to be seeded in the Wimbledon Championship?","a":"DilipBose","b":"Vijay Amritraj","c":"Leander Paes","d":"Mahesh Bhupathi"},{"key":74,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"sports","question":"With which sport would you associate the term ' Nutmeg'?","a":"Basket Ball","b":"Volley Ball","c":"Hand Ball","d":"Foot Ball"},{"key":75,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"sports","question":"What is the new name of the 'White bread round the world Race'?","a":"The Gardencity round the world race.","b":"nan","c":"The Volvo round the world race.","d":"nan"},{"key":76,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"sports","question":"Who scored the first century in limited overs woman's cricket?","a":"Lisa Keightley","b":"Rika Hiraki","c":"Elena Likhotseva","d":"Lisa Raymond"},{"key":77,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"sports","question":"Who was the head of the 'King commission'which was investigated the match fixing","a":"Pieter Strydom","b":"Edwin King","c":"Evans King","d":"Sir King Wessels"},{"key":78,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"sports","question":"With which sport would you associate the 'Prince Rainier Cup?","a":"Croquet","b":"Lacrosse","c":"Tennis","d":"Fencing"},{"key":79,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"sports","question":"Who is the oldest woman to win on the WTA tennis circuit?","a":"Natasha Zverava","b":"Arantxa Sanchez","c":"Martina Navratilova","d":"Elena Likhotseva"},{"key":80,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"sports","question":"What was the original name of modern day tennis?","a":"Tenez","b":"Sphairistike","c":"Jeu de paume","d":"Wings field"},{"key":81,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"sports","question":"Where did India win its first ever hockey gold in the olympic games?","a":"Armsterdam","b":"b","c":"1932","d":"Berlin"},{"key":82,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"sports","question":"Uruguay was the winner of the first ever foot ball world cup. How many more did it win after this?","a":"4 world cups","b":"None","c":"3 world cups","d":"One world cup"},{"key":83,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"sports","question":"In cricket, Which was the 2nd country to win two world cups?","a":"West Indies","b":"Australia","c":"India","d":"SriLanka"},{"key":84,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"sports","question":"When did India first not participate in the Common wealth games?","a":"Brisbane","b":"b","c":" 1986","d":"Cardiff"},{"key":85,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"sports","question":"With which sport would you associate Lance Armstrong?","a":"Cricket","b":"Boxing","c":"Cycling","d":"Polo"},{"key":86,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"sports","question":"Who was the first gold medallist in the history of the Asian Games?","a":"N.C.Kok","b":"Roia Zamani","c":"Kouske Kitajima","d":"Mike Barrowman"},{"key":87,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"sports","question":"How many times has India qualified for  world cup foot ball?","a":"Once","b":"Twice","c":"Thrice","d":"Has not qualified"},{"key":88,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"sports","question":"Who holds the record for  most no of double centuries in test cricket?","a":"Sunil Gavaskar","b":"W .R.Hammond","c":"L.Hutton","d":"Don Bradman"},{"key":89,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"sports","question":"What was the margin of victory when India won the finals of the 1983 Cricket world cup ?","a":"10 Wickets","b":"43 Runs","c":"16 Runs","d":"3 wickets"},{"key":90,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"sports","question":"Who is the first Indian to take a hatrick in test Cricket?","a":"Anil Kumble","b":"Chetan Sharma","c":"Harbhajan singh","d":"Kapil Dev"},{"key":91,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"sports","question":"Which Hockey cup saw the 100th encounter between India and Pakistan?","a":"Sultan Azlan cup","b":"Asian games ","c":"c","d":"d"},{"key":92,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"sports","question":"Who was the first foot baller to receive the 'Adidas Golden Ball'?","a":"D.Maradona","b":"Rossi","c":"Schillaci","d":"Romario"},{"key":93,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"sports","question":"In billiards,what is the line from which the game begins, called?","a":"Mulligan","b":"Crease","c":"Chicane","d":"Baulk"},{"key":94,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"sports","question":"Which is  the second oldest foot ball association?","a":"Scottish FA","b":"The FA of Wales","c":"Irish FA","d":"The English FA"},{"key":95,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"sports","question":"In which series did cricketers first wear colour dress?","a":"Ashes series","b":"Worrel trophy","c":"1987 Reliance World cup","d":"Packer Series"},{"key":96,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"sports","question":"India won two trophies under the captaincy of Kapil Dev.One was the 1983 world cup. Which was the Other?","a":"Benson & Hedges Cup","b":"Asia Cup","c":"Hero Cup","d":"Rothman's Trophy"},{"key":97,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"sports","question":"Who was the first batsman to get out by 'Handling' the ball in the history of Test cricket?","a":"Andrew Hilditch","b":"Russell Endean","c":"Mohsin Khan","d":"Desmond Haynes"},{"key":98,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"sports","question":"Under whose captaincy did India win its first ever test series?","a":"Lala Amarnath","b":"Poly Umrigar","c":"Nari contractor","d":"M.A.K.Pataudi"},{"key":99,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"sports","question":"Who was the oldest boxer to win an olymbic gold?","a":"Dennis Spocffick","b":"Taerna Guria","c":"George Foreman","d":"Nick Davis"},{"key":100,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"sports","question":"Where was the first Asiad held?","a":"New Delhi","b":"Manila","c":"Tokyo","d":"Jakarta"},{"key":1,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Which mechanical device takes its name from the czech word for slavery?","a":"Super computer","b":"Robot","c":"Shoes-maid","d":"Larvent"},{"key":2,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"Where was the first underground nuclear experiment done in India?","a":"Porbunder","b":"Pimpri","c":"Digboi","d":"Pokhran"},{"key":3,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"What is 'dry ice'?","a":"Solid carbon di oxide","b":"solid Nitrogen","c":"Solid oxygen","d":"Solid Hydrogen"},{"key":4,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"Which is India's first scientific satellite?","a":"Apple","b":"Rohini","c":"Aryabhatta","d":"Insat -  1A"},{"key":5,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Who won the nobel prize for physiology \/ medicine in 1902?","a":"C.V.Raman","b":"Sir Ronald Ross","c":"J.C.Bose","d":"Albert Einstein"},{"key":6,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"What is 'Passive Euthanasia'?","a":"Mercy deaths","b":"Murders","c":"Death sentences","d":"Natural deaths"},{"key":7,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"What is the name of the world's first humanoid robot?","a":"R-4","b":" P-2","c":"Humro -1","d":"Jam -7"},{"key":8,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"What is 'ampere' a unit of?","a":"Luminious intensity","b":"Energy","c":"Electric current","d":"Potential difference"},{"key":9,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"How many kilometres make a mile?","a":"1.609 Kms","b":"9.321Kms","c":"3.2459Kms","d":"1.512Kms"},{"key":10,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Who invented Aspirin?","a":"Bajernick","b":"Dreser","c":"Martin Clive","d":"McCollum"},{"key":11,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"Who invented Kidney Machine?","a":"Burkholder","b":"Louis Sokoloff","c":"Kolf","d":"Duggar"},{"key":12,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"On an average,How many decibels of sound does a pneumatic drill makes?","a":"110 db","b":"90 db","c":"140 db","d":"10 db"},{"key":13,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"What is the unit for luminous flux?","a":"Lux","b":"Lumen","c":"Candella","d":"Ohm"},{"key":14,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"What is the unit for Luminous intensity?","a":"Lux","b":"Lumen","c":"Candella","d":"Ohm"},{"key":15,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"What phylum do sponges belong to?","a":"Phylum Mesozoa","b":"Phylum Mollusca","c":"Phylum Porifera","d":"Phylum Echinodermata"},{"key":16,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"What is 'Pathology'?","a":"Study of diseases","b":"Study of ants","c":"Study of fungus","d":"Study of muscles"},{"key":17,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"What do metereologists call a thunder cloud?","a":"Dynomonimbus","b":"Cumulonimbus","c":"Collimonimbus","d":"Numulonimbus"},{"key":18,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"What is analgesic?","a":"A sleeping pill","b":"Antibiotic","c":"Pain killer","d":"Vitamin pill"},{"key":19,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"What is the smallest unit of length known as?","a":"Nanometre","b":"Micrometre","c":"Femtometre","d":"Attometre"},{"key":20,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Who invented the saxophone?","a":"Ruby Sax","b":"Adolph Sax","c":"Lamino Sax","d":"Mikhail Sax"},{"key":21,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"What is the unit for hotness of chilly?","a":"Tezpur units","b":"Scoville heat units","c":"Celbo heat units","d":"Shamrock heat units"},{"key":22,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"What is the 'pinta' a unit of?","a":"Weight","b":"Distance","c":"Length","d":"Volume"},{"key":23,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"In X - rays , What is X stand for?","a":"Un known","b":"Laser","c":"External","d":"Internal"},{"key":24,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"What is the unit for potential difference?","a":"Lux","b":"Volt","c":"Lumen","d":"Ampere"},{"key":25,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"Where is blood formed in the human body?","a":"Heart","b":"Spleen","c":"Bone marrow","d":"Lymph"},{"key":26,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"What is the name of the largest asteroid?","a":"Titania","b":"Jeperes","c":"Lackino","d":"Ceres"},{"key":27,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"Which star is called 'Dog Star'?","a":"Sirius","b":"Venus","c":"Sun","d":"Alpha Centauri"},{"key":28,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"If a pendulum controls a pendulum clock,what controls a watch?","a":"Quartz crystal","b":"Balance wheel","c":"Gravity crystal","d":"Number wheel"},{"key":29,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Which is the scarcest metal found in the world?","a":"Astatine","b":"Rhodium","c":"Osmium","d":"Mercury"},{"key":30,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"In Chemistry, what does 'Fe' stand for?","a":"Iron","b":"Flourine","c":"Copper","d":"Hydrogen"},{"key":31,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"What causes 'Dysentry'?","a":"Plasmodium","b":"Rust","c":"Entamoeba hystolytica","d":"Helminthes"},{"key":32,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"With what was Nicke Appache, the first rocket of ISRO payloaded?","a":"Sodium vapour","b":"Lampblack","c":"CNG","d":"L P G"},{"key":33,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"Which is the strongest bone in the human body?","a":"Skull","b":"Saccrum","c":"Femur","d":"Tarsals"},{"key":34,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"What is the name of the most powerfull super computer made in India?","a":"Param 10","b":"b","c":"000","d":"IB Micro 10"},{"key":35,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Who carried out the first heart transplant?","a":"Craca Michel","b":"Chirstiaan Bernard","c":"Louis Brown","d":"F.W.DeKlork"},{"key":36,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Which is the hardest natural substance?","a":"Graphite","b":"Diamond","c":"Rhodium","d":"Ruby"},{"key":37,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"How many cells does the human brain contain?","a":"15","b":"b","c":"000 billion","d":"25"},{"key":38,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"Who invented the T.V Camera and receiver?","a":"Vladmir Zworykin","b":"John Logie Baird","c":"Comm Bristo","d":"Camico"},{"key":39,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"Who was the first doctor to treat mental illness?","a":"Christiaan Bernard","b":"Benny Thomas","c":"Julia Carney","d":"Philippe Pinel"},{"key":40,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"How many muscles do caterpillers have?","a":"600","b":"1500","c":"2000","d":"1"},{"key":41,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"With what does a jelly fish defend itself?","a":"Crido blasts","b":"Hypostome","c":"Tentacke fish","d":"Sajackit"},{"key":42,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"Which is the only other solar object besides earth to have a nitrogen atmosphere?","a":"Mars","b":"Venus","c":"Lo","d":"Titan"},{"key":43,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"Which is the highest mountain in the solar system?","a":"Popo catepet","b":"Ixaccihuatt","c":"Ojas Delsalado","d":"Olympus Mons"},{"key":44,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Which of the following is a missile?","a":"Sher","b":"Nag","c":"Manjar","d":"Lomdi"},{"key":45,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"Who was the first person to use electricity in Chemistry?","a":"Sir Humphry Dary","b":"Edward Magreth","c":"Faraday Micheal","d":"George Riebou"},{"key":46,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"Who is known as ' The father of Plastic Surgeory?","a":"Baburta","b":"Kuknita","c":"Suknita","d":"Susruta"},{"key":47,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"What is the Moh's scale used to measure?","a":"Temperature","b":"Hardness","c":"Speed of cyclone","d":"Alkalinity"},{"key":48,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"Which gas is responsible for the Bhopal gas tragedy?","a":"Chlorine","b":"Ammonia","c":"Methyl Iso Cyanite ","d":"Alfred Methane"},{"key":49,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"What is the language of the dolphines?","a":"Dolphinese","b":"Niphlodese","c":"Dolphine","d":"It has no language"},{"key":50,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Pantothenic acid is classified under which vitamin?","a":"A","b":"B","c":"C","d":"D"},{"key":51,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"Which scientist is known for  composition of whit light,calculus?","a":"Isaac Newton","b":"Albert Einstein","c":"Stephen Hawking","d":"J.C.Bose"},{"key":52,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"Which is world's first digital computer?","a":"Harvard Mark - 1","b":"E N I A C","c":"I B M","d":"Analyitcal engine"},{"key":53,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Which term is used to mention apes,monkeys and man collectively?","a":"Monkey dynasty","b":"Primates","c":"Orangutan","d":"Marms"},{"key":54,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"What is 'Shagreen'?","a":"Colour","b":"Acid","c":"Fish","d":"Alkali"},{"key":55,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Where would one find the 'Ocean of Storms'?","a":"Jupiter","b":"Earth's moon","c":"Pluto","d":"Titan"},{"key":56,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"Who is a 'Podiatrist'?","a":"Foot specialist","b":"Lung specialist","c":"Calf specialist","d":"Thigh specialist"},{"key":57,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Dialysis is used in the case of patients suffering from which disease?","a":"Heart disease","b":"Kidney diseases","c":"Respiratory disease","d":"Brain diseases"},{"key":58,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"Which astronomer proposed the 'BIG BANG THEORY'?","a":"William Herschel","b":"Copernicus","c":"Cladius ptolemy","d":"Abbe Georges Lemaidre"},{"key":59,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"What is 'Cosmos'?","a":"Universe","b":"A galaxy","c":"Cosmetics","d":"A Chemical"},{"key":60,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"Which unit represents mean distance?","a":"Astronomical unit","b":"Distical unit","c":"Hermann unit ","d":"Hoyles unit"},{"key":61,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"A light year is made of how many astronomical units?","a":"1","b":"000 AUs","c":"50","d":"c"},{"key":62,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"How many degrees of temperature is absoulute zero?","a":"273.16oC","b":"0oC","c":"212oC","d":"-99.99oC"},{"key":63,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"What is the cluster of the 24 galaxies to which the milky way belongs to  known as?","a":"Super 24","b":"The local group","c":"Intergals group","d":"Compo 24"},{"key":64,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"The Black Hole is formed because of which heavenly body?","a":"Asteroids","b":"Stars","c":"Comets","d":"Gravitational pull of moon"},{"key":65,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"What protects earth from solar winds?","a":"Ozone layer","b":"Exosphere","c":"Magnetosphere","d":"Strato sphere"},{"key":66,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"How much time does it take for moon light to reach earth?","a":"3.4 seconds","b":"1.3 seconds","c":"7.2 seconds","d":"1.4 seconds"},{"key":67,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"When is the 'National science day' observed?","a":"28th January","b":"28th December","c":"28th February","d":"28th November"},{"key":68,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"Which among the following is not a gland?","a":"Giberellins","b":"Pituitary","c":"Testes","d":"Adrenal"},{"key":69,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"What is 'PARSEC', a unit of?","a":"Volume","b":"Speed","c":"Distance","d":"Density"},{"key":70,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Which among the following is not the name of a constellation?","a":"Vyadha","b":"Parush","c":"Saptarishi","d":"Kruttika"},{"key":71,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"Who invented the dry cell?","a":"G.Lechlanche","b":"Luigi Galvani","c":"Micheal Faraday","d":"Jerry Jasro"},{"key":72,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Which is world's first all electrical digital computer?","a":"Harvard Mark - 1","b":"ENIAC","c":"IBM","d":"Analytical engine"},{"key":73,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"On which nos is the binary code or language based?","a":"1","b":"b","c":"9","d":"0"},{"key":74,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"For how many hours does a martian day last?","a":"25 hrs","b":"24 hrs","c":"110 hrs","d":"14 hrs"},{"key":75,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"How many months does Mars take to revolve around the Sun?","a":"32","b":"46","c":"23","d":"13"},{"key":76,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"Which was the first successful space craft sent to Mars?","a":"Mars 1","b":"Mars 2","c":"Mariner 3","d":"Mariner 4"},{"key":77,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"What is Filaria caused by?","a":"Ascaris Lumbricoides","b":"Wuchureria Bancrofti","c":"Aurelia","d":"Planaria"},{"key":78,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"What is Oology?","a":"Study of Tumors","b":"Study of wines","c":"Study of Dreams","d":"Study of eggs"},{"key":79,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Which telescope discovered the Black Hole?","a":"Rodger","b":"Hubble","c":"Nicmos","d":"N G S T"},{"key":80,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"What is selenology?","a":"Study of stars","b":"Study of Sun","c":"Study of moon","d":"Study of  comets"},{"key":81,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"Who was the first person to use antiseptics in surgery?","a":"Dr.Arka khan","b":"Dr.Domenic","c":"Derek Walcott","d":"Dr.Joseph Lister"},{"key":82,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"Which one of the following is a type of Fungus?","a":"Topiar","b":"Mozart","c":"Amadeus","d":"Mushroom"},{"key":83,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"What is 'Encephalopathies'?","a":"Diseases of brain","b":"Diseases of eyes","c":"Diseases of heart","d":"Diseases of limbs"},{"key":84,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"Who was the 3rd member of the crew who went along with Neil Armstrong and Edwin Aldrin?","a":"Paul Carr","b":"Collin Mc Milan","c":"Elta James","d":"Micheal Collins"},{"key":85,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"How much time did Armstrong and Aldrin spend on the moon?","a":"2 days 7hrs","b":"2hrs 31 min","c":"5hrs 54 min","d":"7hrs 40 min"},{"key":86,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"What does ' Sputnik' mean?","a":"Traveller","b":"Journalist","c":"Human dreams","d":"Camera man"},{"key":87,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"After making how many revolutions did Sputnik's battery die?","a":"365","b":"326","c":"366","d":"652"},{"key":88,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"Which one of the following is not a kind of group of stars?","a":"Dense star","b":"Single star","c":"Double star","d":"Multiple star"},{"key":89,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"When was the satellite ' Aryabhatta' launched?","a":"1965","b":"1970","c":"1975","d":"1980"},{"key":90,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"Which mineral is called 'Rock Cotton'?","a":"Asbestos","b":"Coal","c":"Bauxite","d":"Manganese"},{"key":91,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Who predicted the wave length of light as it passes through solution?","a":"Subramaniam Chandrasekhar","b":"C.V.Raman","c":"Hargobind Khorana","d":"J.C.Bose"},{"key":92,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Who founded IBM?","a":"Johnson Stone","b":"Charles Flint","c":"Danny Marble","d":"Rijo Jack"},{"key":93,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"What does 'sar' mean in chemistry?","a":"Alkali","b":"Acid","c":"Base","d":"Catalyst"},{"key":94,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Which instrument is used to measure potential difference between two points?","a":"Hygrometer","b":"Volt meter","c":"Barometer","d":"Cup anemometer"},{"key":95,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"Which instrument is used to measure relative density of milk?","a":"Lacometer","b":"Glucometer","c":"Sucrometer","d":"Hygrometer"},{"key":96,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"What is 'Trichloromethane'?","a":"Methyl Iso Cyanite","b":"Alfred methane","c":"Chloroform","d":"Common Salt"},{"key":97,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"Which Indian scientist has worked with Albert Einstein?","a":"Satyendranath Bose","b":"J.C.Bose","c":"C.V.Raman","d":"Abdul Kalam"},{"key":98,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"What is Holstein Freisian?","a":"Mineral","b":"Cow","c":"A very dangerous salt","d":"a muscle"},{"key":99,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"What is the sport of exploring caves called?","a":"Potholing","b":"Caveholing","c":"Mineholing","d":"Nyroholing"},{"key":100,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Which planet in the solar system has the shortest day?","a":"Saturn","b":"Jupiter","c":"Uranus","d":"Neptune"},{"key":101,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"Who invented the polygraph?","a":"John larson","b":"John Mecky","c":"Peter Lindsburg","d":"Thomas Machy"},{"key":102,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"Where was the first medical college estabilished in India?","a":"Chennai","b":"Mumbai","c":"Delhi","d":"Kolkata"},{"key":103,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"Glass is made of which mineral?","a":"Sand","b":"Copper","c":"Mica","d":"Iron"},{"key":104,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"Which planet is called 'The Morning Star'?","a":"Venus","b":"Mars","c":"Pluto","d":"Jupiter"},{"key":105,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Which gas is known as'Laughing gas'","a":"Calcium Oxide","b":"Nitrous Oxide","c":"Aluminium Oxide","d":"Carbon Mono Oxide"},{"key":106,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"Where is the world's longest optical telescope located?","a":"Mt.Semirodriki","b":"Mr.Everest","c":"Camel's Back","d":"d"},{"key":107,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Which gas commonly used in electric bulbs?","a":"Neon","b":"Argon","c":"Krypton","d":"Xenon"},{"key":108,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"Which acid gas is used for killing bacteria?","a":"Sodium vapour","b":"Mercury vapour","c":"Chlorine","d":"Carbon mono oxide"},{"key":109,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"From where is 'Turpentine' obtained?","a":"Alcohol","b":"Sand","c":"Flowers","d":"Wood"},{"key":110,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"What is the formula for 'Ethyl alcohol'?","a":"C6 H12O6","b":"Cu SO4","c":"C2H5OH","d":"Pb(NO3)2"},{"key":111,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"How many bones does the human face have?","a":"21","b":"17","c":"14","d":"9"},{"key":112,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"Which scientist developed a nuclear atomic model on the basis of the result","a":"nan","b":"nan","c":"Lord Rutherford","d":"John Dalton"},{"key":113,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"What is the unit of energy obtained from food?","a":"Joule","b":"Calories","c":"Dyne","d":"Erg"},{"key":114,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"Which element is used as a filament in an electric bulb?","a":"Cuprous","b":"Ferrous","c":"Aurum","d":"Wolfram"},{"key":115,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"What among the following was not invented by Alfred Noble?","a":"Dynamite","b":"Ammonite","c":"Gelignite","d":"Ballistite"},{"key":116,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"Who founded Quantium Mechanics'?","a":"Arnold Sommerfield","b":"Neils Bohr","c":"Werner Heisenberg","d":"Max Born"},{"key":117,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"What was India's first geo stationary communication satellite named?","a":"Pear","b":"Guava","c":"Apple","d":"Melon"},{"key":118,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"What are crystals of hydrated magnesium sulphate called?","a":"Epstein salts","b":"Epsom salts","c":"Epyllion salts","d":"Epizotic salts"},{"key":119,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"What of the formula for kinetic energy?","a":"mgh","b":"mg","c":"1\/2 mv2","d":"mv"},{"key":120,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"What is the double membrane protecting the heart called?","a":"Pericardium","b":"Atrium","c":"Ventricle","d":"Aorta"},{"key":121,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"Which 2 plants grow together with a common thallus, forming lichens?","a":"Algae","b":"b","c":"Riccia","d":"Algae"},{"key":122,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"In which field did Hargobind khorana win his nobel prize?","a":"Physics","b":"Chemistry","c":"Medicine","d":"Biology"},{"key":123,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"What is the M-31 galaxy better known as?","a":"Milky way","b":"Andromeda Nebula","c":"Exado folias","d":"Nepura Jusa"},{"key":124,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"Which is the only natural land form that can be seen clearly from space?","a":"The great barrier reef","b":"Mt.Everest","c":"Grand canyon","d":"Bermuda Triangle"},{"key":125,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"Which is the maximum used muscle?","a":"Tongue","b":"Hand muscles","c":"Leg muscles","d":"Shoulder muscles"},{"key":126,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"What does a rat bite cause?","a":"Plague","b":"Rabies","c":"Foot and mouth disease","d":"Small pox"},{"key":127,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"Who unveiled the 'Quantum Theory'?","a":"Max planck","b":"Blue Baron Max","c":"Red Max","d":"Jerry Max"},{"key":128,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"Which Indian scientist first demonstrated Transmisson of radio waves?","a":"J.C.Bose","b":"C.V.Raman","c":"Abdul Kalam","d":"Homi Bhabha"},{"key":129,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Where was Reserpine invented?","a":"USA","b":"India","c":"Canada","d":"Austria"},{"key":130,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"In the equation e =mc2, which Einstein proposed, what does'c' stand for?","a":"Accelerations","b":"Velocity","c":"Speed of light","d":"Speed of sound"},{"key":131,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"What is the length of a year in Uranus?","a":"30684.8 days","b":"10759.2 days","c":"60190.5 days","d":"91628.6 days"},{"key":132,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"What is an ' Easter Lilly'?","a":"Satellite","b":"Flower","c":"Comet","d":"Space Vehicle"},{"key":133,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"What is the 'Mandible ' better known as ?","a":"Upper jaw bone","b":"Vomer","c":"Lacrimal Bones","d":"Lower jaw bone"},{"key":134,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"What are dentists trained to correct malocclussions known as?","a":"Enthrodendists","b":"Orthodentists","c":"Endodentists","d":"Isodentists"},{"key":135,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"Which is the rarest vitamin deficiency in our body?","a":"A","b":"E","c":"D","d":"K"},{"key":136,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"For which research did Albert Einstein receive a Noble prize?","a":"Theory of relativity","b":"Angular Theory","c":"Photo electric effect","d":"Transmission of waves"},{"key":137,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"Which is the largest muscle in the body?","a":"Tongue","b":"Heart muscles","c":"Glutious Maximus","d":"Sirius Maximus"},{"key":138,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Ganimead is the satellite of which planet?","a":"Saturn","b":"Jupiter","c":"Uranus","d":"Neptune"},{"key":139,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"Which is the only planet in the solar system to have density less than water?","a":"Mercury","b":"Jupiter","c":"Pluto","d":"Saturn"},{"key":140,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"Which was the first unsuccessful satellite to be launched from India?","a":"Rohini","b":"SROSS 1","c":"IRS - P1","d":"GSAT - 1"},{"key":141,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"What is the name given to the position of a planet in its orbit when it is at ","a":"Perihelion","b":"Aphelion","c":"Equinox","d":"Antipode"},{"key":142,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"Which was the first space ship to be landed on an asteroid?","a":"Near Shoemaker","b":"Near Gastaldi","c":"Near Coulthard","d":"Near Montoya"},{"key":143,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"Which was India's first experimental earth observation satellite?","a":"Apple","b":"Rohini","c":"Bhaskara","d":"Aryabhatta"},{"key":144,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"What does 'P' stand for , as in PSLV -D1, PSLV -D2?","a":"Packed","b":"Payloaded","c":"Permanent","d":"Polar"},{"key":145,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"What does'S' stand for .as in GSLV -1 etc?","a":"Satellite","b":"Stationery","c":"Space","d":"Scientific"},{"key":146,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"What was the name of the launching vehicle which lauched the first unsuccesful","a":"Ariane","b":"Delta","c":"Challenger","d":"Ariane - 5"},{"key":147,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"What is  D2O?","a":"Heavy water","b":"Carbonized water","c":"Light water","d":"Liquid glass"},{"key":148,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"What does 'R' in RADAR stand for?","a":"Receiver","b":"Ranging","c":"Radiation","d":"Radio"},{"key":149,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"Who invented the first optical semaphone signalling system?","a":"Ignace Chappe","b":"Adolph sax","c":"Almon B.Stowger","d":"Samuel Morse"},{"key":150,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"Who discovered micro waves?","a":"Arthur Clarke","b":"Alexander Grahambell","c":"John Bardeen","d":"Marconi"},{"key":151,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"Which part of the body is made of the duodenum, Jejiunum and Ileum?","a":"Small Intestine","b":"Heart","c":"Pancreas","d":"Large intestine"},{"key":152,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"Which scientist devised an alcohol thermometer with a graduated scale of 0o to 80oC?","a":"Anders celsius","b":"Gabriel Farenheit","c":"Lord Kelvin","d":"Rena Reaummer"},{"key":153,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"What is the acid or alkali content of a substance measured in?","a":"Ohm","b":"pH","c":"Moh","d":"Dyne"},{"key":154,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"What does pH stand for?","a":"Potential Hydrogen","b":"Potential Helium","c":"Potential Hydrocarbon","d":"Potential Heremandium"},{"key":155,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Who coined the term Information super High way?","a":"Bill Clinton","b":"Al Gore","c":"George Bush","d":"Paul Allen"},{"key":156,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"What does Y & A stand for in the web site YAHOO?","a":"yet another","b":"yamaha acrom","c":"yes and","d":"No expansion"},{"key":157,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"Which was the first asteroid to be discovered?","a":"Lo","b":"Pear","c":"Random","d":"Ceres"},{"key":158,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"Which renewable natural resource is used to generate approximately 75%","a":"Wind","b":"Solar energy","c":"Water","d":"Nitrogen"},{"key":159,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"What is the name of the first remote sensing satellite?","a":"IRS -1 A","b":"BMS -3","c":"RSS-1 A","d":"SRS - PUMA"},{"key":160,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"Who discovered vitamins?","a":"Avit Thomas","b":"Allen","c":"Funk","d":"Reggy Amin"},{"key":161,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"What is Ohm , the unit of ?","a":"Electric current","b":"Resistance","c":"Potential difference","d":"Electromotive Force"},{"key":162,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"The fear of lightning is called Kerauno phobia or \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026?","a":"Phasma phobia","b":"Astraphobia","c":"Arachno phobia","d":"Mania phobia"},{"key":163,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"Which micro organism can turn sunlight in to large quantities of hydrogen gas?","a":"Algae","b":"Bacteria","c":"Fungii","d":"Virus"},{"key":164,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"What was the weight of sputnik?","a":"100 kg","b":"7 tonnes","c":"150 kg","d":"84 kgs"},{"key":165,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"Who discovered the phenomenon of radio - activity?","a":"Heinrich Hertz","b":"Hans Lippershey","c":"Henry Beckquerel","d":"Micheal Faraday"},{"key":166,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"Who built world's first radio telescope?","a":"Grote Reber","b":"Karl Jansky","c":"Hans Lippershey","d":"Galileo"},{"key":167,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"What does 'Mir' mean as in the name of soviet's satellite?","a":"Traveller","b":"Plyer","c":"Peace","d":"Achievment"},{"key":168,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"What does the 'T' stand for as in T-Rays?","a":"Titanium","b":"Tetra -Hertz","c":"Travelling","d":"Titular"},{"key":169,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"What was the name of world's first test tube baby?","a":"Louise Brown","b":"Graca machel","c":"Richard starkey","d":"Chris Patten"},{"key":170,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"Who was the first man to walk in space?","a":"Yuri Gagrin","b":"Neil Armstrong","c":"Micheal collins","d":"Alexi Leonov"},{"key":171,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"What fear immediately develops in a human body after a dog bite?","a":"Hydro phobia","b":"Nycto phobia","c":"Zoo phobia","d":"Cynophobia"},{"key":172,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Ants are insects belonging to which order?","a":"Coelapatra","b":"Hymenoptera","c":"Carantita","d":"Religigama"},{"key":173,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Which is the biggest comet discovered so far?","a":"Gioto","b":"Hale Bapps","c":"Edmund","d":"Halleys"},{"key":174,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"Which is the nearest star to the earth afer the sun?","a":"Sirius","b":"Alphpa centauri","c":"Proxima centauri","d":"Gallery"},{"key":175,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"Who is called the 'Father of the Atom Bomb'?","a":"Robert Oppenheimer","b":"Alfred Noble","c":"Hypolite pixii","d":"Homi Bhaba"},{"key":176,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Which gemstone was earlier named 'adamantine spar'?","a":"Ruby","b":"Sapphire","c":"Diamond","d":"Emerald"},{"key":177,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"What is the conversion of mechanical,electrical or magnetic energy into heat called?","a":"The Erg effect","b":"The Newton effect","c":"The Ohm effect","d":"The Joule effect"},{"key":178,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"What is the colour of hippopotamus' perspiration?","a":"Colourless","b":"Brown","c":"Red","d":"Black"},{"key":179,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Which mineral, over the ages becomes crystallized into marble?","a":"Limestone","b":"Dolomite","c":"Sandstone","d":"Coal"},{"key":180,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Which is the hottest planet in the solar system?","a":"Mercury","b":"Venus","c":"Earth","d":"Uranus"},{"key":181,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"What is the stage of the compressing of dense the galactic nucleus to form a star called?","a":"Protostar","b":"Quasars","c":"Newtron star","d":"Pulsar"},{"key":182,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"What is HO 28185?","a":"A planet beyond solar system","b":"Holland's national obeservatory","c":"A star which looks and works like the sun","d":"Only astroid between Mars and Earth."},{"key":183,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"Which is the planet with the least density?","a":"Mercury","b":"Pluto","c":"Venus","d":"Saturn"},{"key":184,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"What is tide between a high tide and low tide called?","a":"Ebb tide","b":"Neap tide","c":"Tidel Bore","d":"Spring tide"},{"key":185,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"What is a Loo, a Mistral, a Chinook, a Sirrocco, a Bora ,a Purga, a Bise, a yamo?","a":"Precipitaiton","b":"Mountains","c":"The layers of atmosphere","d":"Winds"},{"key":186,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"What does the 'P' in the DPT vaccine stand for?","a":"Pneumonia","b":"Polio","c":"Pertussis","d":"Pulmonary"},{"key":187,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"What does '.de' stand for in the world of internet?","a":"Denmark","b":"Germany","c":"Switzerland","d":"Washington"},{"key":188,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"What is the fear of surgery known as?","a":"Tomophobia","b":"Carcino phobia","c":"Jacophobia","d":"Agyro phobia"},{"key":189,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"With what would you associate INCOSPA?","a":"Nutrition","b":"Natural resources","c":"Space Research","d":"Physics"},{"key":190,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Which is the largest constituent of air?","a":"Oxygen","b":"Nitrogen","c":"Carbon dioxide","d":"Hydrogen"},{"key":191,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"What is  Nimbus a type of?","a":"Star","b":"Galaxy","c":"Constellation","d":"Cloud"},{"key":192,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"Which liquid is commonly used in the thermometer?","a":"Water","b":"Bromine","c":"Mercury","d":"Chlorine"},{"key":193,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"Which gas is used in Balloons?","a":"Helium","b":"Hydrogen","c":"Oxygen","d":"Neon"},{"key":194,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"What does 'S' in AIDS stand for?","a":"Spread","b":"Satiate","c":"Syndrome","d":"Surmount"},{"key":195,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"What is the unit of specs?","a":"None","b":"Diaptus","c":"Specules","d":"Radiut"},{"key":196,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"What did Tim Burner Lee invent in the IT world?","a":"HTTP","b":"HTML","c":"WWW","d":"Web cam"},{"key":197,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Who is the first Indian woman to go to space?","a":"Diana Hayden","b":"Kalpana Chawla","c":"Gauri Kashikor","d":"Aparna Sculi"},{"key":198,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"Which is the brightest star?","a":"Rhoughes","b":"Sun","c":"Alpha-centauri","d":"sirus"},{"key":199,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"In the solar system what does the Cassini division separate?","a":"inner and outer plants","b":"Rings of Uranus","c":"Rings of Saturn","d":"Sun and Mercury"},{"key":200,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Which ustable gas takes its name from Greek for 'I smell'?","a":"Choride","b":"Ozone","c":"Nitrogen","d":"Butane"},{"key":201,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"Which is the largest artery in the body?","a":"Aorta","b":"Renal Artery","c":"Pulmonary Artery","d":"Pachidom"},{"key":202,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"Which is the largest vein in the body?","a":"Pulmonary vein","b":"Renal Vein","c":"Superior Vena cava","d":"Superior Arto Cava"},{"key":203,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"In the human body, the Eustachian tube connects the middle ear to which other part?","a":"Nose","b":"Throat","c":"Eyes","d":"Brain"},{"key":204,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Iron and Copper are two out of the three metals contained by the ore pyrrhotite.Which is the third one?","a":"Aluminium","b":"Nickel","c":"Zinc","d":"Lead"},{"key":205,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"Which is the second hardest substance on earth?","a":"Corundum","b":"Ruby","c":"Sapphire","d":"Emarald"},{"key":206,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"Who is known as 'Father of modern computers'?","a":"John Napier","b":"IBM","c":"Charles Babbage","d":"Peter Paulis"},{"key":207,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"What is the unit of work?","a":"Dyne","b":"Newton","c":"Lux","d":"Erg"},{"key":208,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Which is the heaviest particle amongst Alpha,Beta & Gamma particles?","a":"Beta","b":"Alpha","c":"Gamma","d":"All are equal"},{"key":209,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"What is the biological name for Vitamin B12 ?","a":"Niacin","b":"Thiamine","c":"Pyridoxine","d":"Cynacobalamin"},{"key":210,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"Which is the simplest form of carbohydrates?","a":"Starch","b":"Fructose","c":"Lactose","d":"Sucrose"},{"key":211,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"What are gases with antiseptic properties called?","a":"Crying gases","b":"Laughing gases","c":"Hot gases","d":"Inert gases"},{"key":212,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"Charles Konrad,Richard F.Cordon and Allan Elvini. What is so special about this crew?","a":"Second to land on the moon","b":"Discovered Pluto","c":"Invented cloning","d":"Died while heading towards the Sun"},{"key":213,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"Which Indian died in the space shuttle Columbia, which disentigrated in space in 2003?","a":"Rakesh Sharma","b":"Kalpana Iyer","c":"Kalpana Chawla","d":"Kalpana Dutt"},{"key":214,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"Who was Rakesh Sharma?","a":"Mission Specialist","b":"Shuttle controller","c":"Director of Shuttle","d":"Squadron leader"},{"key":215,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Which acid is used in call batteries?","a":"Nitric acid","b":"Sulphuric acid","c":"Hydrochloric acid","d":"Folic acid"},{"key":216,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"Where was the first Automatic Telephone Exchange set up?","a":"USA","b":"UK","c":"India","d":"USSR"},{"key":217,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"What do we get when cathode rays are obstructed?","a":"Pontgen rays","b":"Alpha rays","c":"Beta rays","d":"Gamma rays"},{"key":218,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"Which meter shows the altitude of a plane from the sea level?","a":"Planometer","b":"Hitometer","c":"Altimeter","d":"Hygrometer"},{"key":219,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"What is the method of pricking the tissues of the body with fine needles for medical treatment called?","a":"Hystosation","b":"Ethnoraty","c":"Finleyture","d":"Acupuncture"},{"key":220,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Which is the tiniest bone in the human body?","a":"Pinna","b":"Stebis","c":"Femur","d":"Finger bones"},{"key":221,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"From where was India's first satellite 'Aryabhatta' launched?","a":"Bearson Lake","b":"Shriharikota","c":"Kourou","d":"America"},{"key":222,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Which was India's first successful remote sensing satellite?","a":"SROSS 1","b":"INSAT - 1D","c":"INSAT-2B","d":"SROSS-4"},{"key":223,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"Which acid is for melting gold?","a":"Sulphuric acid","b":"Nitric Acid","c":"Hydrochloric acid","d":"Aqua Regia"},{"key":224,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"What is a machine, which plays a song when a coin is inserted ,called?","a":"Gramaphone","b":"Walkdostray","c":"Juke box","d":"Mackcondy"},{"key":225,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"From which tree is Quinine obtained?","a":"Chinchona tree","b":"Banyan tree","c":"Mahagony","d":"Babool"},{"key":226,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Towards which direction does a magnet always point to?","a":"South","b":"North","c":"East","d":"West"},{"key":227,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"With which invention would you associate Elisa Otis?","a":"Escalator","b":"Gane","c":"Elevator","d":"Bull - Dozer"},{"key":228,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"Which gland is responsible for secretion of tears?","a":"Pituitary gland","b":"Thyroid gland","c":"Adrenal gland","d":"Lachrymal gland"},{"key":229,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"What does the R in SROSS, stand for?","a":"Radioactive","b":"Radar","c":"Rohini","d":"Remote sensing"},{"key":230,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"Who prepared the first Periodic Table for classification of elements?","a":"Mendeleyev","b":"Moseley","c":"J J Thompson","d":"Neils Bohr"},{"key":231,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"How many bones are present in an infant's vertebrae?","a":"24","b":"33","c":"17","d":"21"},{"key":232,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"Which one of the following bones is  not found in the limbs?","a":"Pattela ","b":"Lina","c":"Fibila","d":"Cranium"},{"key":233,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"Where were fingerprints first used as a method of identification?","a":"France","b":"Brazil","c":"Argentina","d":"Australia"},{"key":234,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"What does the 'R' stand for as in SARS?","a":"Respiratory","b":"Rheumatic","c":"Rust","d":"Rot"},{"key":235,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"Who invented the 'Microscope'?","a":"John Walker","b":"James Puckle","c":"Z.Janssen","d":"E.Cart Wright"},{"key":236,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Which disease was so surely eradicated that  the Indian government promised Rs.1000\/-for","a":"Polio","b":"Small pox","c":"Tuberculosis","d":"Jaundice"},{"key":237,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"How much sound is made be the rustle of leaves?","a":"5db","b":"7db","c":"10db","d":"14db"},{"key":238,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"If -273.15 0C is absolute zero in celsius, then how many Kelvins make absolute zero?","a":"-459.7K","b":"273.15K","c":"0 K","d":"373.15K"},{"key":239,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Which among the following items has the highest potential hydrogen ie 14?","a":"Baking soda","b":"Caustic soda","c":"Washing soda","d":"Vinegar"},{"key":240,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"How is Vitamin B12 also known as?","a":"Cyanacobalamin","b":"Retinol","c":"Folic acid","d":"Pyridoxine"},{"key":241,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Glucose is stored as glucogen in which part of the body?","a":"Heart","b":"Liver","c":"Kidneys","d":"Pancreas"},{"key":242,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"What are citrus fruits rich in?","a":"Vitamin C","b":"Iron","c":"Iodine","d":"Vitamin A"},{"key":243,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"Aneamia is caused due to the lack of which mineral?","a":"Calcium","b":"Phosphorous","c":"Iron","d":"Iodine"},{"key":244,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"Cochlea is an essential organ for which activity?","a":"Hearing","b":"Vision","c":"Taste","d":"Touch"},{"key":245,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"In which space shuttle did Rakesh Sharma travel?","a":"Voslok-1","b":"Gemini -4","c":"Salyut - 7","d":"Soyuz T-11"},{"key":246,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"What happens to the weight of iron, when it rusts?","a":"It increases","b":"It Increases & then decreases","c":"It decreases","d":"It remains the same"},{"key":247,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"Who discovered the laws of gravitation?","a":"Galileo","b":"Copernicus","c":"Newton","d":"Eintein"},{"key":248,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"What is leprosy caused by?","a":"Virus","b":"Fungii","c":"Helminth","d":"Bacteria"},{"key":249,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"What is Pencillin produced from?","a":"Bacteria","b":"Virus","c":"Fungus","d":"Protozoans"},{"key":250,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"Who discovered 'Radium'?","a":"Sir Alexander Fleming","b":"James Watt","c":"Madam Curie","d":"Sir Joseph Lister"},{"key":251,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"The Indian Satellite Anuradha was place in space by which space shuttle?","a":"Challanger","b":"Apollo","c":"GSLV","d":"PSLV"},{"key":252,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"Which of the following is not a form of sulphur?","a":"Plastic sulphur","b":"Monoclinic sulphur","c":"Prusimatic sulphur","d":"Hopping sulphur"},{"key":253,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Which blood group is called Universal Recipient?","a":"O","b":"AB","c":"A","d":"B"},{"key":254,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"Which blood group is called Univeral donar?","a":"AB","b":"B","c":"A","d":"O -"},{"key":255,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"Which is the toughest part of the body?","a":"Femur","b":"Skull","c":"Enamel","d":"Corchea"},{"key":256,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"science","question":"What is the duration of human pregnancy?","a":"40-45 weeks","b":"30-35 weeks","c":"50-55 weeks","d":"60-65 weeks"},{"key":257,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"Which countryy pioneered the treatment of acupuncture?","a":"India","b":"Japan","c":"N.Korea","d":"China"},{"key":258,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"science","question":"Which instrument is used for measuring blood pressure?","a":"Opthalmoscope","b":"Sphygmo manometer","c":"Barometer","d":"Stethoscope"},{"key":259,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"science","question":"What is the Chief constituent of gobar gas?","a":"Nitrogen","b":"CO2","c":"Ethane","d":"Methane"},{"key":260,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"science","question":"What is the chemical name for limestone?","a":"Ca(OH)2","b":"CaCl2","c":"CaCO3","d":"Ca2(OH)4"},{"key":1,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"politics","question":"The Airport , in which Indian city is named after Chatrapati Shivaji?","a":"Pune","b":"Mumbai","c":"Nagpur","d":"Solapur"},{"key":2,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"politics","question":"With which country would you associate the aeroline airport?","a":"Australia","b":"USA","c":"Austria","d":"USSR"},{"key":3,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"politics","question":"What is the Japanese style of flower arrangement called?","a":"Origami","b":"Dirgea","c":"Ikebana","d":"Jendia"},{"key":4,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"politics","question":"What does article 243A refer to?","a":"Zilla parishad","b":"Gram sabha","c":"Gram Panchayat","d":"Municipality"},{"key":5,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"politics","question":"Where did the Jerusalem bomb blast in 1997?","a":"Romantica market","b":"Hazimina market","c":"Nimlanya market","d":"Yehuda market"},{"key":6,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"politics","question":"Which country has the largest postal network ?","a":"Russia","b":"Canada","c":"Bangaladesh","d":"India"},{"key":7,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"politics","question":"How many neighbours does China Have?","a":"9","b":"7","c":"14","d":"13"},{"key":8,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"politics","question":"What was Harare previously known as?","a":"Salisbury","b":"Bathurst","c":"Dahomey","d":"Congo"},{"key":9,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"politics","question":"What is the other name for Latin America?","a":"North America","b":"Brazil","c":"South America","d":"Chile"},{"key":10,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"politics","question":"Amartya Sen was awarded the 1998 Nobel Prize in Economics for his contribution in which field?","a":"Financial economics","b":"Development economics","c":"International economics","d":"Welfare economics"},{"key":11,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"politics","question":"What is the currency in Denmark?","a":"Kwanza","b":"Krone","c":"Karuna","d":"Hyniva"},{"key":12,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"politics","question":"Which is the last month of the Indian national calender?","a":"Chaitra","b":"Magha","c":"Pausha","d":"Phalguna"},{"key":13,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"politics","question":"Where would you find the Sentinalese tribes?","a":"Andaman & Nicobar Islands","b":"Western Somoa","c":"Nigeria","d":"Australia"},{"key":14,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"politics","question":"Who is the longest serving chief minister in India?","a":"Jyoti Basu","b":"J.Jayalalitha","c":"Laloo Prasad Yadav","d":"Farooq Abdulla"},{"key":15,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"politics","question":"Which is the second largest island in the world?","a":"Indonesia","b":"United Kingdom","c":"New Guinea","d":"Srilanka"},{"key":16,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"politics","question":"If you were touring Otterup, in which country would you be?","a":"Denmark","b":"Russia","c":"France","d":"Portugal"},{"key":17,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"politics","question":"Who was the first woman Chief justice of the High court?","a":"Ida Schuddar","b":"Padma Vidya","c":"Shannon Kaur","d":"Leila Seth"},{"key":18,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"politics","question":"Names of how many Indian states and features are mentioned in the National anthem?","a":"10","b":"12","c":"14","d":"16"},{"key":19,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"politics","question":"What is the capital of Chattisgarh?","a":"Raipur","b":"Dehradun","c":"Ranchi","d":"Rajghat"},{"key":20,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"politics","question":"Which is the least populated city in the world?","a":"Tuvalu","b":"Palau","c":"Naira","d":"Vatican city"},{"key":21,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"politics","question":"What is the Great wall of China known in chinese?","a":"Kiang Watus","b":"Chang Cheng","c":"Sutara Chiang","d":"Chingo Chalio"},{"key":22,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"politics","question":"What is the technical term applied to a government run by a woman?","a":"Womanarchy","b":"Gyanarchy","c":"Evarchy","d":"Lacharcy"},{"key":23,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"politics","question":"When does the Chinese New year begin?","a":"4th January","b":"4th February","c":"4th March","d":"4th April"},{"key":24,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"politics","question":"Which is the highest award of the Ottaman empire?","a":"Thakrusha","b":"Gasha","c":"Sasha","d":"Pasha"},{"key":25,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"politics","question":"Which article of the Indian constitution prevents the attorney general from voting?","a":"88","b":"72","c":"51A","d":"63"},{"key":26,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"politics","question":"Who has composed the tune for Srilanka's national anthem?","a":"Ranasinghe Prema dasa","b":"Arjuna Ratnayike","c":"Varadaraja Perumal","d":"A.Samarakone"},{"key":27,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"politics","question":"Who was the first national poet of Bangladesh?","a":"Ravindranath Tagore","b":"Kazi Nazrul Islam","c":"Hassan Imam","d":"Zakir Zulran"},{"key":28,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"politics","question":"Who was the first woman to become a Chief minister in an Indian state ?","a":"Nandini Satpaty","b":"Sushila Khadokar","c":"Sucheta Kripalani","d":"Syeda Anwara"},{"key":29,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"politics","question":"When were the first general Loksabha election held?","a":"1949","b":"1952","c":"1950","d":"1947"},{"key":30,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"politics","question":"How many officially recognized languages does India have?","a":"32","b":"14","c":"18","d":"19"},{"key":31,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"politics","question":"When was India's National Anthem adodpted by its Contituent assembly?","a":"26th January 1950","b":"24th January 1952","c":"26th January 1952","d":"24th January 1950"},{"key":32,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"politics","question":"In which country would you find the 'Palace of Wonders'?","a":"Tanzania","b":"Zanzibar","c":"Nyasa","d":"Tang anyka"},{"key":33,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"politics","question":"What is the parliament of Iceland known as?","a":"Slothing","b":"Byning","c":"Althing","d":"Notting"},{"key":34,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"politics","question":"Which country is known as 'Land of Lillies'?","a":"Australia","b":"UK","c":"Norway","d":"Canada"},{"key":35,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"politics","question":"Which among the following is not an emirate of UAE?","a":"Khaliduja","b":"Umm - AlOtuvain","c":"Ajman","d":"Ras-Al-Khaimah"},{"key":36,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"politics","question":"Where is the head quarters of WHO?","a":"New york","b":"Paris","c":"Geneva","d":"Stockholm"},{"key":37,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"politics","question":"Which state in North East India means 'Land of the Rising Sun'?","a":"Tripura","b":"Arunachal pradesh","c":"Meghalaya","d":"Assam"},{"key":38,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"politics","question":"In which country were the first railways built?","a":"France","b":"Britain","c":"Denmark","d":"Germany"},{"key":39,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"politics","question":"Which portfolio among the following was not held by I.K.Gujral?","a":"Broadcasting","b":"Prime minister","c":"External affairs","d":"Education"},{"key":40,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"politics","question":"Which city is known as 'Gateway of Tamil Nadu'?","a":"Tuticorin","b":"Cape Comerin","c":"Chennai","d":"Pondicherry"},{"key":41,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"politics","question":"Which city is known as'Manchester of South India'?","a":"Bangalore","b":"Mysore","c":"Coimbatore","d":"Kochi"},{"key":42,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"politics","question":"What is the parliament of Norway called?","a":"Atting","b":"Slothing","c":"Sting","d":"Evereshedthing"},{"key":43,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"politics","question":"Which country is  called the 'Sugar Bowl' of the world?","a":"Belgium","b":"Cuba","c":"Brazil","d":"India"},{"key":44,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"politics","question":"What is the currency of Tuvalu?","a":"Tuvalun doller","b":"Colon","c":"Franc","d":"Australian dollar"},{"key":45,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"politics","question":"Which one of the flowers  is the national flower of Ireland?","a":"Cherry Blossom","b":"Maple","c":"Shanrock","d":"Orchid"},{"key":46,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"politics","question":"Where is the consulate of USA situated in Mumbai?","a":"Washington house","b":"Jefferson house","c":"Bushmush house","d":"Lincoln house"},{"key":47,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"politics","question":"Which is the largest state in India?","a":"Madhya Pradesh","b":"Rajasthan","c":"Andhra Pradesh","d":"Uttar Pradesh"},{"key":48,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"politics","question":"Which country was previously known as Kampuchea?","a":"Cambodia","b":"Korea","c":"Benin","d":"Guyana"},{"key":49,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"politics","question":"Which Indian politician's memoirs are titled 'Flight to the parliament?","a":"Abdul Kalam","b":"BalaYogi","c":"I.K.Gujral","d":"Rajesh Pilot"},{"key":50,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"politics","question":"Which country has a flag with different symbols of pictures printed on both sides?","a":"Uruguay","b":"Paraguay","c":"Bosnia","d":"Herzegorina"},{"key":51,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"politics","question":"How many stanzas are there in the song from which our  national anthem was taken?","a":"7","b":"5","c":"2","d":"1"},{"key":52,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"politics","question":"Which article of the Indian constitution relates particularly to Jammu and Kashmir?","a":"368A","b":"352C","c":"370","d":"270"},{"key":53,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"politics","question":"What does the first schedule of the Indian contituition comprise of?","a":"Language of India","b":"Official religions","c":"Oaths and affirmations","d":"States & Union territories"},{"key":54,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"politics","question":"How many amendments were made to the Indian constituition till the year 2000?","a":"89","b":"53","c":"90","d":"91"},{"key":55,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"politics","question":"What is the election symbol of Samata Party?","a":"Hammer","b":"Cycle","c":"Fire Lamp","d":"Arrow"},{"key":56,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"politics","question":"Who was the first Lok sabha Speaker?","a":"M.A.Iyyangar","b":"G.V.Mavalankar","c":"Hukani singh","d":"G.S.Dhillon"},{"key":57,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"politics","question":"What is the Capital of Uruguay?","a":"MonteCarlo","b":"Monte Video","c":"Adis Ababa","d":"Frankfurt"},{"key":58,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"politics","question":"Which politician is nicknamed 'Dubiya'?","a":"Laloo Prasad Yadav","b":"Yoshiro Mori","c":"Hosni Mubarak","d":"George Bush"},{"key":59,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"politics","question":"Who was the first US president to move into the White House?","a":"George Washington","b":"Thomas Jefferson","c":"John Adams","d":"George Bush Sr."},{"key":60,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"politics","question":"Who was the first woman to become a minister in the union cabinet of India?","a":"Indira Gandhi","b":"Sucheta Kripalani","c":"Sarojini Naidu","d":"Rajkumari Amrit Kaur"},{"key":61,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"politics","question":"Which African nation has its name meaning 'Black' in Arabic?","a":"Sudan","b":"Nigeria","c":"Lesotho","d":"Kenya"},{"key":62,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"politics","question":"Which two countries are linked by the Karakoram highway?","a":"India and China","b":"India and Pakistan","c":"China and Pakistan","d":"China and Nepal"},{"key":63,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"politics","question":"What is the Parliament of Japan called?","a":"Nest","b":"Diet","c":"Althing","d":"Stothing"},{"key":64,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"politics","question":"The abacus in the Indian emblem consists of 4 animals.They are the elephant,the bulls, a horse and \u2026\u2026?","a":"Tiger","b":"Lion","c":"Peacock","d":"Panther"},{"key":65,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"politics","question":"In which session was India's national anthem first sung?","a":"Calcutta","b":"Bombay","c":"Nagpur","d":"Chennai"},{"key":66,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"politics","question":"Where was India's first industrial strike held?","a":"VT Railway station","b":"Chennai Central Railway station","c":"Howrah Railway station","d":"Bangalore railway station"},{"key":67,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"politics","question":"Who is the 'Head of state' of New zealand?","a":"Queen Elizabeth II","b":"Dame Silvia Cartwright","c":"Helen Clark","d":"Arnoldo Aleman"},{"key":68,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"politics","question":"What is the currrency of Guinea?","a":"Guindy","b":"Guinea dollar","c":"Quetzal","d":"Franc"},{"key":69,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"politics","question":"Who was the first scientist to become the president of India?","a":"A.P.J.Abdul Kalam","b":"Shankar D.Sharma","c":"K.R.Narayanan","d":"Dr.Rajendra Prasad"},{"key":70,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"politics","question":"Who is called 'Father of Modern Japan'?","a":"Sumodi Kusho","b":"Mushti Hudo","c":"Yang Man Dan","d":"Surdi Fu-kalit"},{"key":71,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"politics","question":"Who was the first woman Prime minsiter?","a":"Srimao Bandaranaike","b":"Indira Gandhi","c":"Masumeh Ebtekar","d":"Chandrika Kumaratunge"},{"key":72,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"politics","question":"Which country is called the 'Roof of the world'?","a":"Turkey ","b":"Tasmania","c":"Tanzania","d":"Tibet"},{"key":73,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"politics","question":"Which country has the shortest national anthem, with just 4 lines?","a":"Australia","b":"Pakistan","c":"Japan","d":"China"},{"key":74,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"politics","question":"Who was the first woman Chief minister of Tamil Nadu?","a":"J.Jayalalitha","b":"Janaki Ramachandran","c":"Fathima beevi","d":"Sashikala "},{"key":75,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"politics","question":"Which of the following departments is not under the Govt of India?","a":"Ministry of Textiles","b":"Department of electronics","c":"Department of Ocean development","d":"Ministry of Literature"},{"key":76,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"politics","question":"The 'Taskent Declaration' was signed between Lal Bahadur Shastri & \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026?","a":"Ayub Khan","b":"Benazir Bhutto","c":"Iskandar Mirza","d":"Nawaz Sharif"},{"key":77,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"politics","question":"In SAARC, what do the word SAA stand for?","a":"South American Association","b":"South African Association","c":"South Asian Association","d":"South Atlantic Association"},{"key":78,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"politics","question":"Which party did Bangladeshi PM, Begum Khaleda Zia Belong to?","a":"Bangla deshi National Party","b":"Awami League","c":"Mukti Bahini","d":"Jamaat-e-Islami"},{"key":79,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"politics","question":"Which declaration was signed between A B Vajpayee and Iranian President Mohd Khatami?","a":"Tabriz Declaration","b":"Mashhad Declaration","c":"Esfahan Declaration","d":"Tehran Declaration"},{"key":80,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"politics","question":"Which is the most populous district in India?","a":"Thane","b":"Medinapur","c":"Mumbai Suburban","d":"Pune"},{"key":81,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"politics","question":"What is the currency of Bangladesh?","a":"Taka","b":"Kata","c":"Rupee","d":"Dollar"},{"key":82,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"politics","question":"White Lily is the emblem of which country?","a":"Japan","b":"Australia","c":"Canada","d":"Germany"},{"key":83,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"politics","question":"Blue Book is the official book of which nation?","a":"UK","b":"USA","c":"USSR","d":"Canada"},{"key":84,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"politics","question":"What is the parliament of Isreal known as?","a":"Knesset","b":"Diet","c":"Storing","d":"Athing"},{"key":85,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"politics","question":"Which place is called 'Roof top of the World'?","a":"The pamirs","b":"China","c":"India","d":"Pakistan"},{"key":86,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"politics","question":"Which country is called 'The land of The Rising sun'?","a":"Vietnam","b":"Australia","c":"Japan","d":"Thailand"},{"key":87,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"politics","question":"Which country is called the 'Land of White Elephants'?","a":"Thailand","b":"Australia","c":"Japan","d":"Vietnam"},{"key":88,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"politics","question":"What  are the New-Zealanders known as?","a":"Emus","b":"Kiwis","c":"Doves","d":"Ostiches"},{"key":89,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"politics","question":"What is the national animal of Australia?","a":"Kangaroo","b":"Leopard","c":"Lion","d":"Panther"},{"key":90,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"politics","question":"Where is the longest  railway platform in India?","a":"Mumbai","b":"Madras","c":"Madurai","d":"Mittgaon"},{"key":91,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"politics","question":"Which state in India has the highest percentage of literacy?","a":"Goa","b":"Manipur","c":"Meghalaya","d":"Kerala"},{"key":92,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"politics","question":"38th parallel divides which two countries?","a":"Vietnam & Compuchea","b":"North Korea&South Korea","c":"India & China","d":"North America & South America"},{"key":93,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"politics","question":"Who is the founder of the political party AIADMK?","a":" Vaiko                                                ","b":"M.G.Ramachandran","c":"Ramdass","d":"Jeyalalitha"},{"key":94,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"politics","question":"What is the capital of Uganda?","a":"Kampala","b":"Tel-Aviv","c":"Beunos Aires","d":"Jamaica"},{"key":95,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"politics","question":"What is Egypt's currency?","a":"Riyal","b":"Dinar","c":"Egyptian pound","d":"Egyptian Dollar"},{"key":96,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"politics","question":"Which among the following is a commercial street in India ?","a":"Malkous street","b":"Dalal Street","c":"Silicon Valley","d":"Elgin Street"},{"key":97,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"politics","question":"Which country is known as the 'Pearl of the Carribean sea'?","a":"West Indies","b":"Cuba","c":"Madagascar","d":"Hawaii Island"},{"key":98,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"politics","question":"Which dictatoral president of Cuba,did Fidel Castro overthrow to take power?","a":"Batista","b":"Glafcos","c":"Ruz","d":"Stipe Mesie"},{"key":99,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"politics","question":"Which country is Lesotho's only neigbour?","a":"Namibia","b":"Isreal","c":"Zimbabwe","d":"South Africa"},{"key":100,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"politics","question":"Who was the first speaker of the Loksabha?","a":"G.V.Mavlankar","b":"M.A.Iyengar","c":"S.Hukum singh","d":"Neelam S.Reddy"},{"key":1,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"geography","question":"What is the name given  to the two days ina year when the days and nights are equal?","a":"Equilibirum","b":"Eganimisceses","c":"Equinox","d":"Elga"},{"key":2,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"geography","question":"Which is the southernmost point in India where the Arabian sea and the Bay of Bengal meet?","a":"Indira point","b":"Cape comerin","c":"Kochi","d":"Nayla"},{"key":3,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"geography","question":"Which water body is known as Bengal's sorrow?","a":"R.Dane","b":"Bay of Bengal","c":"R.Ganga","d":"R.Damodar"},{"key":4,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"geography","question":"Which is the only state of USA that is not in the mainland?","a":"Hawaii","b":"Alaska","c":"Michigan","d":"California"},{"key":5,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"geography","question":"Which is the highest peak in South America?","a":"Bonete","b":"Tupungato","c":"Ojas Del Salado","d":"Aconcagua"},{"key":6,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"geography","question":"Which geographer devised the convention of using 90o parallel lines for latitudes and longitudes?","a":"Claudius Ptolemy","b":"Sebastian Munster","c":"Gerhard Mercator","d":"Jacobo Gastaldi"},{"key":7,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"geography","question":"Which is the smallest state in India?","a":"Goa","b":"Orissa","c":"Kerala","d":"Tripura"},{"key":8,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"geography","question":"What is the Sea of Galilee?","a":"Sea","b":"River","c":"Lake","d":"Bay"},{"key":9,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"geography","question":"Which is the largest desert in India?","a":"Thar","b":"Sahara","c":"Safar","d":"Gobi"},{"key":10,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"geography","question":"Who was the first person to reach the North pole?","a":"Robert E. Peary","b":"Raden Suharto","c":"Thaksin Mallin","d":"Johnson Nato"},{"key":11,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"geography","question":"Which is the longest beach in the world?","a":"Marina","b":"Cape of Good Hope","c":"Cape comerin","d":"Rio -de -Jeniero"},{"key":12,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"geography","question":"Which is world's largest river island?","a":"Nile","b":"Majuli","c":"Tasmania","d":"Malauri"},{"key":13,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"geography","question":"Who was the first man to conquer Mt. Everest twice?","a":"Tensing sherpa","b":"Babu Chichri","c":"Nawang Gombu","d":"Baji Sherpa"},{"key":14,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"geography","question":"At which rank does River Ganga stand in the world's longest Rivers?","a":"30th","b":"19th","c":"7th","d":"28th"},{"key":15,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"geography","question":"Which is the second largest island in the world?","a":"Indonesia","b":"Greenland","c":"New guinea","d":"United Kingdom"},{"key":16,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"geography","question":"Where would you find the Larsen B ice shelf?","a":"Antartica","b":"Moscow","c":"Jammu & Kashmir","d":"Sahara Desert"},{"key":17,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"geography","question":"What is the passage between South America and Antaritica known as?","a":"Ross passage","b":"Weddell passage","c":"Theodore passage","d":"Drake passage"},{"key":18,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"geography","question":"Which is the largest peninsula in the world?","a":"South India","b":"Arabia","c":"Alaska","d":"Labrador"},{"key":19,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"geography","question":"Which is the deepest cave in the world?","a":"Resseu du foillis","b":"Sistema Hautla","c":"Snezhnaya","d":"Resseu de la pierre st"},{"key":20,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"geography","question":"What is the deepest point of the deepest trench, Marinana known as?","a":"Vityaz II","b":"Galathea deep","c":"Challenger deep","d":"Planet deep"},{"key":21,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"geography","question":"What is earth's escape velocity ie.the speed necessary to break away from earth into outer space?","a":"11km\/hr","b":"11min\/sec","c":"11km\/sec","d":"11miles\/hr"},{"key":22,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"geography","question":"What are the Micronesian,Melanesian and Polynesian islands together known as?","a":"Assai","b":"Voldesium","c":"Peninistia","d":"Oceania"},{"key":23,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"geography","question":"What are the houses in Prairie regions called?","a":"Tupic","b":"Igloo","c":"Yurt","d":"Namahale"},{"key":24,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"geography","question":"Which union territory in India has its major towns in three different states?","a":"Dadra and Nagar Haveli","b":"Pondicherry","c":"Daman and Diu","d":"Chandigarh"},{"key":25,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"geography","question":"Which among the following is not a landlocked country?","a":"San Marino","b":"Nepal","c":"Lesotho","d":"Portugal"},{"key":26,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"geography","question":"Which peak is the second highest in the world?","a":"K-2","b":"Mt.Cook","c":"Ojas-Del-Salado","d":"Nanga Parbhat"},{"key":27,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"geography","question":"Which is the second smallest state in India?","a":"Tribura","b":"Nagaland","c":"Sikkim","d":"Mizoram"},{"key":28,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"geography","question":"Which is the most populated state india?","a":"Bihar","b":"Uttar Pradesh","c":"Maharashtra","d":"West Bengal"},{"key":29,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"geography","question":"How many islands does India have in all?","a":"204","b":"247","c":"219","d":"252"},{"key":30,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"geography","question":"Which is the northern most point of Asia?","a":"Cape Baba","b":"Cape Dezhnyor","c":"Malay Peninsula","d":"Cape Chelyuskin"},{"key":31,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"geography","question":"Which is the largest lake in Asia?","a":"Aral sea","b":"Caspian Sea","c":"Dead sea","d":"Baikal"},{"key":32,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"geography","question":"The Lonar lake in Maharashtra was formed due to which natural activity?","a":"Glacial Movement","b":"Tectonic movement","c":"Volcanic activity","d":"Aeolean process"},{"key":33,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"geography","question":"Where in Assam is the Kaziranga National Park?","a":"Jorhat","b":"Barpet","c":"Tezpur","d":"Difu"},{"key":34,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"geography","question":"Every state of USA has a nickname except one .Which one is it?","a":"District of Columbia","b":"Delaware","c":"Nevada","d":"Missouri"},{"key":35,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"geography","question":"What is the capital of New York?","a":"Concord","b":"Albary","c":"Lincoln","d":"Boston"},{"key":36,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"geography","question":"Which is the second largest continent with respect to area?","a":"Europe","b":"North America","c":"Antartica","d":"Africa"},{"key":37,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"geography","question":"Which is the smallest state of the commonwealth of Australia?","a":"Nieu Islands","b":"New Zealand","c":"Murry","d":"Tasmania"},{"key":38,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"geography","question":"Which is the largest lake in North America?","a":"Lake Michigan","b":"Lake Hunon","c":"Great Bear","d":"Lake Superior"},{"key":39,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"geography","question":"Which is the second largest city in the World?","a":"Mumbai","b":"Tokyo","c":"Shanghai","d":"New york"},{"key":40,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"geography","question":"What is the name of the volcano causing the loudest explosion?","a":"Barren Island","b":"Cotopaxi","c":"Krakotoa","d":"Titicaca"},{"key":41,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"geography","question":"What is the name of the largest crater formed by a volcano?","a":"Josata","b":"Toba","c":"Sajut","d":"Red marine"},{"key":42,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"geography","question":"Who was the first man to visit the South pole?","a":"Robert peary","b":"Nozmi","c":"Danny Kaye","d":"Amundsen"},{"key":43,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"geography","question":"What is the Mt.Everest known as in China?","a":"Qomolangma","b":"Chang cheng","c":"Gobirochista","d":"Gu-ti cha"},{"key":44,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"geography","question":"What is Mt.Everest Known as in Nepal?","a":"Maha Paravata","b":"Ratasha","c":"Sagar Matha","d":"Rajini"},{"key":45,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"geography","question":"What is Mt.Everest known as in Tibet?","a":"Long cha","b":"Aramani","c":"Mi-ti gu-ti-cha-pu long-na","d":"Ki-La-Chu ka-Fi -Da"},{"key":46,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"geography","question":"What does a Fujita scale measure?","a":"Heat intensity","b":"Volcanic erruption","c":"Storm intensity","d":"Ultra violet ray intensity"},{"key":47,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"geography","question":"What is the term for representation of round earth on a flat map?","a":"Projection","b":"Latution","c":"Longution","d":"Lamination"},{"key":48,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"geography","question":"Which South American country borders Guyana,French Guyana and Brazil?","a":"Chile","b":"Suriname","c":"Paraguay","d":"Uruguay"},{"key":49,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"geography","question":"Djibouti's importance as a port is related to its location on a busy shipping route leading to what canal?","a":"Panama canal","b":"Baffin Canal","c":"Benin Canal","d":"Suez Canal"},{"key":50,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"geography","question":"Which state in India is bordered by Nepal, Bhutan and Tibet?","a":"Arunachal Pradesh","b":"Sikkim","c":"Meghalaya","d":"Manipur"},{"key":51,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"geography","question":"Mumbai was known as the city of how many islands?","a":"Seven","b":"Eight","c":"Two","d":"Four"},{"key":52,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"geography","question":"In which island would one find the Cherbanian Reef?","a":"Andaman","b":"Nicobar","c":"Mumbai","d":"Lakshadweep"},{"key":53,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"geography","question":"How many Indian states does China border?","a":"7","b":"8","c":"5","d":"6"},{"key":54,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"geography","question":"What kind of mountain are the Himalayas?","a":"Volcanic mountain","b":"Fold mountain","c":"Tectonic mountain","d":"Leakage mountain"},{"key":55,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"geography","question":"Which is the most inaccessible peak in the world?","a":"K2","b":"Kanchenjunga","c":"Kilimanjaro","d":"Mc Kinley"},{"key":56,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"geography","question":"Where is the 'Diamond harbour'?","a":"Cape town","b":"Melbourne","c":"Kolkata","d":"Abynia"},{"key":57,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"geography","question":"Where is the Dakshin Gangotri?","a":"Cape comerin","b":"Antartica","c":"Russia","d":"USA"},{"key":58,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"geography","question":"How do we better know Godwin Austin Mountains?","a":"K2","b":"Alps","c":"Pirpunjal","d":"Appachin"},{"key":59,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"geography","question":"Which is India's longest beach?","a":"Diamond Harbour","b":"Marine Drive","c":"Chowpatty","d":"Marina"},{"key":60,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"geography","question":"Which is the largest bay in the world?","a":"Baffin bay","b":"Bay of Bengal","c":"Baltic bay","d":"Hudson Bay"},{"key":61,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"geography","question":"Which is the largest island in the North Atlantic ocean?","a":"Great Britain","b":"New Foundland","c":"Iceland","d":"Ireland"},{"key":62,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"geography","question":"What was the initial unseparated land in the world known as?","a":"Laurasia","b":"Gondwanaland","c":"Tethys","d":"Pangea"},{"key":63,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"geography","question":"Who described the concept of 'Continental Drift'?","a":"Alfred wegener","b":"Theophrastus Hohenheim","c":"Paracelsus","d":"Adelina Domingues"},{"key":64,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"geography","question":"Which of the following pauses do not exist in the atmosphere?","a":"Tropopause","b":"Strato pause","c":"Ionopause","d":"Mesopause"},{"key":65,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"geography","question":"There is only one country in the Indian Ocean, featuring in the list of the top of ten smallest countries ,Which is it?","a":"Nauru","b":"Maldives","c":"Srilanka","d":"Japan"},{"key":66,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"geography","question":"Where would you find the ozone layer?","a":"Stratosphere","b":"Mesosphere","c":"Ionosphere","d":"Toposphere"},{"key":67,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"geography","question":"Which is the longest tributary of River Ganga?","a":"R.Son","b":"R.Yamuna","c":"R.Ramganga","d":"R.Kosi"},{"key":68,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"geography","question":"Who devised the successful technique of 'Green Revolution'?","a":"G.B.John","b":"Norman E.Borlaug","c":"Simon Bolivar","d":"Thomas Becket"},{"key":69,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"geography","question":"Which is the highest peak in the continent of Africa?","a":"Margerita","b":"Ebgon","c":"Toubkal","d":"Kilimanjaro"},{"key":70,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"geography","question":"Which is the longest river in China?","a":"Huage He","b":"Salween","c":"Chang Tiang","d":"Tsang Po"},{"key":71,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"geography","question":"Which is the most saline sea in the world?","a":"Van","b":"Dead Sea","c":"Caspian Sea","d":"Red Sea"},{"key":72,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"geography","question":"Which is the second smallest continent in the world?","a":"Australia","b":"Europe","c":"Antartica","d":"Africa"},{"key":73,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"geography","question":"Greenwich, whose time is accepted as the world standard time, is situated on the banks of which river?","a":"R.Thames","b":"R.Rhine","c":"R.Siene","d":"R.Weser"},{"key":74,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"geography","question":"What is Kimberley in South Africa famous for?","a":"Platinum","b":"Gold","c":"Silver","d":"Diamond"},{"key":75,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"geography","question":"Which city is known as the 'Sea of Rivers' with five rivers flowing through it?","a":"Nagasaki","b":"Hiroshima","c":"Warsaw","d":"Vienna"},{"key":76,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"geography","question":"Which is the source of the 'Blue Nile'?","a":"Lake Victoria","b":"Lake Albert","c":"Lake Tana","d":"Lake Edward"},{"key":77,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"geography","question":"Which river forms the Angel Waterfalls, the highest in the world?","a":"R.Negro","b":"R.Amazon","c":"R.Japura","d":"R.Carrao"},{"key":78,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"geography","question":"Which river forms the Victoria falls?","a":"R.Zambezi","b":"R.Cubango","c":"R.Cuando","d":"R.Shire"},{"key":79,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"geography","question":"What is the fertile area in a desert known as?","a":"Abyss","b":"Oasis","c":"Aar","d":"Beaufort"},{"key":80,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"geography","question":"What is the place, where a river meets the sea, called?","a":"Bank","b":"Mouth","c":"Aviary","d":"Estuary"},{"key":81,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"geography","question":"What are lines joining places of the same height above sea - level called?","a":"Contours","b":"Isobars","c":"Isanes","d":"Meccadors"},{"key":82,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"geography","question":"What are natives of the Kalahari desert known as ?","a":"Kaladis","b":"Aborigenes","c":"Bushmen","d":"Eskimos"},{"key":83,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"geography","question":"What is the land joining two larger pieces of land, known as ?","a":"Gulf","b":"Isthmus","c":"Muscoor","d":"Strait"},{"key":84,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"geography","question":"Which is the largest lake in India?","a":"Vembanad","b":"Kolleru","c":"Pulicat","d":"Chilka"},{"key":85,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"geography","question":"Which is the highest waterfall in India?","a":"Jog","b":"Manimuthar","c":"Mundhanthurai","d":"Kalakad"},{"key":86,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"geography","question":"Which is the  largest artificial lake in India?","a":"Nath-sagar","b":"Mani-sagar","c":"Raj-Sagar","d":"Govind - sagar"},{"key":87,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"geography","question":"Which is the highest peak in Argentina?","a":"Ojas-Del-Salado","b":"Tupungato","c":"Aconcagua","d":"Liulliaco"},{"key":88,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"geography","question":"'Mansarovar' is situated near which lake?","a":"Dal","b":"Sambhar","c":"Wular","d":"Rakas"},{"key":89,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"geography","question":"Which is the highest peak in the Aravalli mountain ranges?","a":"Gurushikar","b":"Dupgarh","c":"Panchmarhi","d":"Mt.Abu"},{"key":90,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"geography","question":"Which is the southernmost point of South America?","a":"Cape of Good Hope","b":"CapeComerin","c":"Cape Horn","d":"Cape Mendonza"},{"key":91,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"geography","question":"There are two islands near southern South America, belonging to the UK, South Georgia is one,","a":"St. Helena","b":"Falkland Islands","c":"Calcos Islands","d":"St.Lucia"},{"key":92,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"geography","question":"Which range of mountains separate Europe from Asia?","a":"Ural Mts.","b":"Vlan Batier","c":"Pamir","d":"Mt.Murnask"},{"key":93,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"geography","question":"Which continent has the lowest population?","a":"North America","b":"Australia","c":"South America","d":"Antartica"},{"key":94,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"geography","question":"Which is the deepest trench in the  Indian Ocean?","a":"Mariana Trench","b":"Java Trench","c":"Puerto Rico Trench","d":"Indon Trench"},{"key":95,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"geography","question":"Which river flows through Washington?","a":"Hudson","b":"Thames","c":"Clyde","d":"Potomaz"},{"key":96,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"geography","question":"How many neighbours does Madhya pradesh have?","a":"3","b":"4","c":"5","d":"6"},{"key":97,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"geography","question":"Which one among the following is a Kayal?","a":"Vembanad","b":"Thakkad","c":"Periyar","d":"Pambiyar"},{"key":98,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"geography","question":"Which is the longest river in the Indian Plateau?","a":"Krishna","b":"Beema","c":"Cauveri","d":"Godavari"},{"key":99,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"geography","question":"India has two bays, One is the bay of Bengal, which is the other?","a":"Bay of Kachch","b":"Palk Bay","c":"Bay of Mannar","d":"Kaladi Bay"},{"key":100,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"geography","question":"Which is the southernmost point of India?","a":"Cape Comerin","b":"Poin Pedro","c":"Indira Point","d":"Narcondam"},{"key":101,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"geography","question":"With which state is the 'Silent Valley Project associated?","a":"Assam","b":"Kerala","c":"Madhya Pradesh","d":"Karnataka"},{"key":102,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"geography","question":"The ancient irrigation dam Kallanai in Tamil Nadu is across which river?","a":"Tambarabarani","b":"Vaigai","c":"Palaru","d":"Cauvery"},{"key":103,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"geography","question":"Which is the longest dam in India?","a":"Hirakud","b":"Jaikawadi","c":"Damodar","d":"Bakra - Nangal"},{"key":104,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"geography","question":"Which is the tallest dam in India?","a":"Jaikawadi","b":"Hirakud","c":"Bakra","d":"Nangal"},{"key":105,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"geography","question":"Where would one find the 'Malaprabha' project?","a":"Kerala","b":"Karnataka","c":"Tamil Nadu","d":"Maharashtra"},{"key":106,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"geography","question":"Where would one find the 'Kudremukh Iron Ore' project?","a":"Kerala","b":"Karnataka","c":"Tamil Nadu","d":"Andhra Pradesh"},{"key":107,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"geography","question":"Mahatma Gandhi Setu', the longest bridge in Asia has been built across which river?","a":"Kosi","b":"Ganga","c":"Yamuna","d":"Gaghara"},{"key":108,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"geography","question":"Where was coal mining first started in India?","a":"Talcher coalfields","b":"Singrauli coalfields","c":"Karanpura coal fields","d":"Raniganj"},{"key":109,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"geography","question":"The number one sugar producing country in the world?","a":"Cuba","b":"India","c":"UK","d":"USA"},{"key":110,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"geography","question":"What are lines conecting places receiving equal amount of rainfall called?","a":"Isohels","b":"Contours","c":"Isobar","d":"Isotherms"},{"key":111,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"geography","question":"Where is the Atacama Desert?","a":"Chile","b":"South Africa","c":"Australia","d":"New Zealand"},{"key":112,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"geography","question":"Which continent has the lowest population?","a":"Antartica","b":"Australia","c":"Europe","d":"South Africa"},{"key":113,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"geography","question":"What is the deepest point of the Atlantic ocean known as?","a":"Challenger Deep","b":"Soyuz Deep","c":"Milwaukee Deep","d":"Kwajelin Deep"},{"key":114,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"geography","question":"Who was the first mountaineer to climb all 14 mountains of the world with a height of above 8000mts?","a":"Allan Hinkes","b":"Reinhold Messner","c":"Alison Hargreaves","d":"Edmund Hillary"},{"key":115,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"geography","question":"Which is the highest peak in Antartica?","a":"Puncak Jaya","b":"Mt.Elbrus","c":"Vinson Massif","d":"Aconcagua"},{"key":1,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"books","question":"How many Oscar nominations did the film'All About Eve' receive?","a":"8","b":"11","c":"22","d":"14"},{"key":2,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"books","question":"Who directed the eleven oscar winning film, Ben Hur?","a":"William Wyler","b":"Steven Speilsberg","c":"Richard Attenbourgh","d":"Sam Mendes"},{"key":3,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"books","question":"In the comic strip 'Garfield', what is John's profession?","a":"Doctor","b":"Clerk","c":"Cartoonist","d":"Vetenerian Doctor"},{"key":4,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"books","question":"Who holds the record for being the most nominated artist?","a":"Julia Roberts","b":"Nicole Kidman","c":"Halle Berry","d":"Katherine Hepburn"},{"key":5,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"books","question":"In which year, during the 20th century was no national award given for the best film category?","a":"1990","b":"1978","c":"1962","d":"1951"},{"key":6,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"books","question":"What is the expansion of STAR as  in the TV channel, STAR NETWORK?","a":"Satellite TV Asian Region Limited","b":"Satellite Transferred Asian Recordings","c":"System of TV Airing Recordings","d":"There is no expansion"},{"key":7,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"books","question":"On which novel is the film Abhay based on?","a":"Psycho","b":"Dayam","c":"Sivagami En Selvan","d":"Kiraku"},{"key":8,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"books","question":"Which was the first talkie feature film made in India?","a":"Alam Ara","b":"Kalidas","c":"Bhakta Prahalata","d":"Balan"},{"key":9,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"books","question":"Who was the first Indian to win an Oscar?","a":"Satyajit Ray","b":"Shyam Benegal","c":"Bhanu Athaiya","d":"Dadasaheb Phalke"},{"key":10,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"books","question":"Which was the first Marathi film to receive a national award?","a":"Pundalik","b":"King of Ayodhya","c":"Vilasi Ishwar","d":"Shyaamchi Aai"},{"key":11,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"books","question":"Which is R.K.Lakshman's first cartoon character?","a":"You said it","b":"Comman man","c":"Siole jury","d":"Sputnik I"},{"key":12,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"books","question":"The novel ' Untouchable' covers the events in a single day of which boy?","a":"Bakha","b":"Swami","c":"Alu","d":"Fagin"},{"key":13,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"books","question":"Who wrote the book \"Jurrassic Park'?","a":"Steven Speilberg","b":"Charlotte Bronte","c":"Walter Scott","d":"Micheal Crichton"},{"key":14,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"books","question":"Who among the following has not played the role of James Bond?","a":"David Niven","b":"George Lazenby","c":"Timothy Dalton","d":"Kevin Spacey"},{"key":15,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"books","question":"Which super hero did Jerry Seigal and Joe Schuster create for?","a":"Batman","b":"Superman","c":"Spiderman","d":"James Bond"},{"key":16,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"books","question":"Who wrote 'Ben - Hur'?","a":"Lewis Wallace","b":"Lewis Caroll","c":"David Halberstam","d":"Irving Rasau"},{"key":17,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"books","question":"What does the 'R' in Archies T-Shirts stand for?","a":"Rambo","b":"River Dale","c":"Raven Ravago","d":"Reggie"},{"key":18,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"books","question":"How do we better know Norma Jean Mortenson?","a":"Julia Roberts","b":"Marylyn Monroe","c":"Hilary Swank","d":"Britney Spears"},{"key":19,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"books","question":"Who designed the cartoon character'Mickey Mouse'?","a":"Ub.Ewerks","b":"Ouviero Toscani","c":"Walt Disney","d":"W.C.Fields"},{"key":20,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"books","question":"On which mountain did the fictional character Rip - Van Winkle sleep?","a":"Makaradu Mountain","b":"Catsgill mountain","c":"Gondi Mountain","d":"Jaden mountain"},{"key":21,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"books","question":"Who directed the 8 minute moving picture 'The Great Train Robbery'?","a":"Guglielmo","b":"James Joyce","c":"Bolshevik","d":"Edwin S. Porter"},{"key":22,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"books","question":"What is the French equivalent of the Oscars?","a":"Cegar","b":"Cedor","c":"Censor","d":"Cesar"},{"key":23,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"books","question":"Who designed the Oscar awards?","a":"Cedric Gibbons","b":"Oliviero Toscani","c":"Ub.Ewerks","d":"Sebastian Stephen"},{"key":24,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"books","question":"Which character int the novel 'Untouchable' is a latrine cleaner?","a":"Bakha","b":"Aziz","c":"Alu","d":"Swami"},{"key":25,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"books","question":"Which was director Satyajit Ray's last film?","a":"Seemabaddha","b":"Sonar Kella","c":"Agantuk","d":"Charulata"},{"key":26,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"books","question":"What was Satyajit Ray's pet name?","a":"Heera","b":"Manik","c":"Chamu","d":"Janaa"},{"key":27,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"books","question":"The Oscars,Emmy and Grammy are three of the four American top entetertainment awards.","a":"Bony","b":"Chony","c":"Lony","d":"Tony"},{"key":28,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"books","question":"Who is the only entertainer to have received all four Oscar,Grammy,Emmy and Tony awards?","a":"Whoopi Goldberg","b":"Gyneth Paltrow","c":"Rota Moreno","d":"Cameron Diaz"},{"key":29,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"books","question":"Who composed the music for Richard Attenbourgh's Oscar winning film'Gandhi'?","a":"Phil Collins","b":"Pandit Ravishankar","c":"Zakir Hussain","d":"Carlos Santano"},{"key":30,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"books","question":"Who directed the Tele serial 'Malgudi days'?","a":"Shankar Nag","b":"Mani Ratnam","c":"Sharada","d":"Ashok Giligini"},{"key":31,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"books","question":"Which country recently took offence at the way it was depicted in an episode of 'The Simpsons'?","a":"USA","b":"France","c":"Mongolia","d":"Brazil"},{"key":32,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"books","question":"What awards were called 'Quick before they Crook' awards by late director Billy Wilder?","a":"Best actor in a negative role","b":"Lifetime awards","c":"Special awards","d":"Critic's awards"},{"key":33,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"books","question":"Which famous character did Jeppotto create?","a":"Pinochio","b":"Doller","c":"Mickey Mouse","d":"Shaggy"},{"key":34,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"books","question":"In the book Harry Potter, what is the name given to a  person not knowing magic?","a":"Moron","b":"Mafiacorza","c":"Mugle","d":"Mosh"},{"key":35,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"books","question":"Pandit Ravishankar colaborated with which violinist to make the album East speaks West?","a":"Yahudi Mehelmen","b":"Travin Pal","c":"Aylam Iroja","d":"Piranha Sion"},{"key":36,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"books","question":"Who is the writer of 'Fire in the Mountain'?","a":"Anita Desai","b":"Ruskin Bond","c":"Arundhati Roy","d":"Manjula Padmanabhan"},{"key":37,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"books","question":"For which book did Arundhati Roy receive the Bookers Prize in 1998?","a":"Algebra of Infinite Injustice","b":"Albha and\u2026\u2026","c":"Ramesses","d":"The God of Small Things"},{"key":38,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"books","question":"Who wrote 'Gullivers Travels'?","a":"Charles Dickens","b":"George B.Shaw","c":"Jonathan Swift","d":"David Longfellow"},{"key":39,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"books","question":"What is the name of Popeye's girl friend?","a":"Ariel","b":"Olive Oyl","c":"Jane","d":"Velma"},{"key":40,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"books","question":"What is the name of Richie Riche's girl friend?","a":"Veronica","b":"Jane","c":"Gloria","d":"Ariel"},{"key":41,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"books","question":"Which comic character is also associated with kit, devil and aero?","a":"Spiderman","b":"He-Man","c":"Turboman","d":"Phantom"},{"key":42,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"books","question":"Which breed of dog is Scooby Doo?","a":"Alsacian","b":"Lorraine","c":"Feata Amir","d":"Great Dane"},{"key":43,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"books","question":"How do we better know Lord Grey Stroke?","a":"Tarzen","b":"George of Jungle","c":"Superman","d":"Batman"},{"key":44,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"books","question":"Who wrote 'The Road Ahead?","a":"Arundhati Roy","b":"Bill Gates","c":"Ian Botham","d":"Dick cheney"},{"key":45,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"books","question":"Who wrote 'Geetanjali'?","a":"B.Chandra Chatterjee","b":"Kalidasa","c":"R.Tagore","d":"Jotirao Phule"},{"key":46,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"books","question":"Bram stoker's book 'Dracula' is about an evil count in which city?","a":"Tasmania","b":"Pennsylvania","c":"Transylvania","d":"Argentina"},{"key":47,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"books","question":"How do we better know Julia Elizabeth Wells?","a":"Julie Andrews","b":"Julia Roberts","c":"Julie chiristie","d":"Jane Fonda"},{"key":48,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"books","question":"Who was the first reciepient of the Oscar award for best actress?","a":"Bette Davis","b":"Jean Harlow","c":"Marylin Monroe","d":"Janet Gaynor"},{"key":49,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"books","question":"Who directed the eight minute super hit film,'The Great Train Robbery'?","a":"Bram stoker","b":"Steven Speilsberg","c":"Edwin S Porter","d":"Johm Ford"},{"key":50,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"books","question":"Who was the first film maker from Bengal to work in the west?","a":"Satyajit Ray","b":"Premankur Atorthy","c":"Shyam Benegal","d":"Dhirubhi Shah"},{"key":51,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"books","question":"Mr.Plod is the policeman of which fictional place?","a":"Toyland","b":"Wonderland","c":"Waterland","d":"Airland"},{"key":52,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"books","question":"Who wrote the lyrics to 'Rolling Stones' hit 'I wanna be your man'?","a":"John lennon","b":"Elton John","c":"Micheal Jackson","d":"Vinnegut"},{"key":53,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"books","question":"Which is the biggest book in the world?","a":"Woods& Williams","b":"The little Red Book","c":"8 feet tall","d":"English Major"},{"key":54,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"books","question":"Where were the first talking movies made?","a":"USA","b":"India","c":"UK","d":"France"},{"key":55,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"books","question":"Which was the first non-dialogue film in the Indian history of cinema?","a":"Alam Ara","b":"Indra","c":"Pesum Padam","d":"Manicha"},{"key":56,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"books","question":"How do we better know Kaminker?","a":"Judy Garland","b":"Simone Signoret","c":"Lana Turner","d":"Betty Grable"},{"key":57,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"books","question":"Whose autobiography is 'Daughter of the east'?","a":"Phoolan Devi","b":"Indira Gandhi","c":"Benazir Bhutto","d":"P.T.Usha"},{"key":58,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"books","question":"Who is the author of 'Crescent Moon'?","a":"Aurobindo Ghosh","b":"Mulkraj Anand","c":"Mahatma Gandhi","d":"Ravindranath Tagore"},{"key":59,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"books","question":"Which book has its first line as 'All children,except one grow up'?","a":"Alice in wonderland","b":"Coolie","c":"The Jungle Book","d":"Peter Pan"},{"key":60,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"books","question":"Who is the author of the 'Panchatantra'?","a":"Buddha","b":"Vishnu Sharma","c":"Valmiki","d":"Vyasa"},{"key":61,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"books","question":"Which was William Shakespeare's first play?","a":"Henry VI part 1","b":"Richard III","c":"Richard II","d":"Henry V"},{"key":62,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"books","question":"Which was William Shakespeare's Last play?","a":"Cymbeline","b":"Henry VIII","c":"The Tempest","d":"Macbeth"},{"key":63,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"books","question":"In which play of William Shakespeare was Miranda a principle character?","a":"Cymbeline","b":"The Tempest","c":"The winter's tale","d":"Macbeth"},{"key":64,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"books","question":"Who is the author of 'The Thirteenth Sun'?","a":"Amrita Pritam","b":"Aruntati Roy","c":"Mulk Raj Anand","d":"V.S.Naipaul"},{"key":65,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"books","question":"Which novel did not consist of a single 'e'?","a":"Faraway music","b":"Sohrab & Rustom","c":"Out of Africa","d":"Gadsby"},{"key":1,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"Whom did commander Mir Jafar betray at the 'Battle of Plassey' ?","a":"Siraj - Ud-Daula","b":"Akbar","c":"Aurangazeb","d":"Shivaji"},{"key":2,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"By which emperor was the city of Fatepur Sikhri built?","a":"Jehangir","b":"Shahjahan","c":"Babur","d":"Akbar"},{"key":3,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"Who was the first person to become a Prime minister?","a":"Jawaharlal Nehru","b":"Winston Churchill","c":"Sir Robert Walpole","d":"Martin Luther"},{"key":4,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"Who was the founder of the 'Scouts and Guides movements' ?","a":"Max Meuller","b":"Joseph Lister","c":"Robert Baden Powell","d":"George Meuller"},{"key":5,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"Who was the first woman Vice President of Iran?","a":"Hemus Betak","b":"Aylam Iroja","c":"Massumeh Ebtekar","d":"Makla Telkar"},{"key":6,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"What is the middle name of Nelson Mandela?","a":"Guy","b":"Vyachaslev","c":"Martin","d":"Rolihlala"},{"key":7,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"Who was the President of India from 1982-87?","a":"Shankar Dayal Sharma","b":"Giani Zail Singh","c":"B.D.Jatti","d":"Varahagiri Venkata Giri"},{"key":8,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"How do we better know Manikarnika?","a":"Annie Besant","b":"Madam Cama","c":"Rani Lakshmi bai","d":"Kasturba Gandhi"},{"key":9,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"If Gandhiji was born in 1869 at Porbhandar, where was Kasturba Gandhi born?","a":"Porbandar","b":"Madras","c":"Calcutta","d":"Poona"},{"key":10,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"At what age did Swami Vivekananda die?","a":"40","b":"20","c":"39","d":"23"},{"key":11,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"In which year did Ravindranath Tagore receive a Bharat Ratna?","a":"1923","b":"1941","c":"He did not receive one","d":"1987 (posthomous)"},{"key":12,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"When were nobel prizes first awarded?","a":"1907","b":"1906","c":"1904","d":"1901"},{"key":13,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"How do we better know the 'Pygmalion Point' ?","a":"Victoria point","b":"Indira point","c":"Gate point","d":"Jyoti point"},{"key":14,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"How much money was Gandhiji fined for burning foreign goods?","a":"Rs.1","b":"000.00","c":"Rs.100.00","d":"Rs.50.00"},{"key":15,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"Which country shares its Independence Day with India?","a":"North Korea","b":"South Korea","c":"Cambodia","d":"Ecuador"},{"key":16,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"Which woman started Mother's Day?","a":"Anna Jarvis","b":"Katherine","c":"Santa Moore","d":"Mother Teresa"},{"key":17,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"Who made Mother's Day an official holiday?","a":"George Hanning","b":"Woodrow Wilson","c":"Grafton Greeves","d":"John Seiko"},{"key":18,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"Who is the only man whose birth day is a legal holiday in every state of USA?","a":"Abraham Lincoln","b":"George Washington","c":"Thomas Jefferson","d":"Patrick Henry"},{"key":19,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"Who designed the Washington Monument?","a":"Chris Jade","b":"Robert Mills","c":"Ben Quake","d":"Kilaeu Nickelson"},{"key":20,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"With which emperor is the 'Sepoy Mutiny ' associated?","a":"Bahadur Shah Zafar II","b":"Adilshah","c":"Nizamshah","d":"Sher Shah Sur"},{"key":21,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"Who was the first Indian lady doctor?","a":"Savithribai Phule","b":"Anandi Bai Joshi","c":"Kasturba Gandhi","d":"Jijamata"},{"key":22,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"After which occasion does the 'Beating Retreat' take place?","a":"Independence day","b":"Army day","c":"Republic day","d":"Boxer's day"},{"key":23,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"What was the name of sage Valmiki when he was a bandit?","a":"Manaraka","b":"Bamasura","c":"Ratnakara","d":"Jalukara"},{"key":24,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"Who started the journal 'Vande Mataram'?","a":"Annie Besant","b":"Madame Bhikaji Cama","c":"Lokmanya Tilak","d":"Gopal Krishna Gokhale"},{"key":25,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"Which nationalist leader produced the first ever statistical estimate of P.C.I in India?","a":"Sardar Vallabhai Patel","b":"Abul Kalam Azad","c":"Gopal Krishna Gokhale","d":"Dadabhai Nowroji"},{"key":26,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"In 1759 ,which city replaced Marmagao as the seat of the Portuguese government? ","a":"Pondicherry","b":"Mahe","c":"Panjim","d":"Diu"},{"key":27,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"Name of how many soldiers are inscribed on the India gate?","a":"14724","b":"15001","c":"16420","d":"13515"},{"key":28,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"In which city was Jehangir Tata born?","a":"Chandigarh","b":"Paris","c":"Moscow","d":"London"},{"key":29,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"Who is the writer of Ashtadyayi, the earliest existing grammatical treatise on Sanskrit?","a":"Sant Dyaneshwar","b":"Vyasa","c":"Valmiki","d":"Panini"},{"key":30,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"Which gate in Delhi was renamed 'Victoria Gate' after the recapture of the city in 1857?","a":"Lahore gate","b":"India gate","c":"Delhi Sur gate","d":"Jigna gate"},{"key":31,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"In Ragamala paintings, which raga is normally depicted by overcast skies and clouds?","a":"Akash Raga","b":"Asman Malhar","c":"Megh Malar","d":"Megh Raga"},{"key":32,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"Who is the architect of the Mughal Gardens at the viceral lodge?","a":"Edwin Lutyens","b":"Stephen Baker","c":"Charles.C. Boycott","d":"Irwin Daniel"},{"key":33,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"What is the second name of Magellan?","a":"Fernando ","b":"Thames","c":"Thomas","d":"Ferdinand"},{"key":34,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"What is Birla house, the place where Gandhiji died now known as?","a":"Rajghat","b":"Gandhi niwas","c":"Gandhi sadan","d":"Ekthasthal"},{"key":35,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"Which of th following is said to be ' Heaven's Gate'?","a":"Ratul","b":"Satul","c":"Batul","d":"Natul"},{"key":36,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"From where was Vande Mataram taken?","a":"Rajitaranjini","b":"Anandmath","c":"Akbarnama","d":"Akbarkosha"},{"key":37,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"According to legends,which tree did the Indus people worship?","a":"Neem tree","b":"Peepal tree","c":"Banyan tree","d":"Teak tree"},{"key":38,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"Who was the most distinguished Hindi poet in Akbar's court?","a":"Birbal","b":"Tansen","c":"Abdur Rahim Khan - I-Khana","d":"Raja Bhagwan Das"},{"key":39,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"Where was Jawaharlal Nehru born?","a":"Delhi","b":"Allahabad","c":"Baroda","d":"Jaipur"},{"key":40,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"Who founded the 'Mysore Wadiyar'dynasty?","a":"Chikka Devaraja","b":"Yaduraya","c":"Nalvadi Krishnaraja","d":"Mummadi Krishnaraja"},{"key":41,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"From which language are Urdu and Hindi derived?","a":"Zaban-e-urdu-muala","b":"Bundeli","c":"Khariboli","d":"Awadhi"},{"key":42,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"What was Afghanistan originally knownas?","a":"Ariana","b":"Taraki","c":"Naijibu","d":"Burhan"},{"key":43,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"When was Pearl Harbour attacked?","a":"1939","b":"1941","c":"1943","d":"1945"},{"key":44,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"What is the name of the veda associated with music?","a":"Natya veda","b":"Samaveda","c":"Yajurveda","d":"Atharva veda"},{"key":45,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"When was the 'Vernacular Press Act' passed?","a":"1881","b":"1878","c":"1892","d":"1861"},{"key":46,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"What was Chankya also known as?","a":"Alwarez","b":"Nirad","c":"Kautilya","d":"Chaucer"},{"key":47,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"What was the sobriquet previously given to Afghanistan ?","a":"Khorazam","b":"Khorachana","c":"Khoranim","d":"Khorasan"},{"key":48,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"According to Egyptians,where would the mummies ultimately reach?","a":"Kingdom of Osiris","b":"Kingdom of Nut","c":"Sun disc paradise","d":"Kingdom of Ramesses"},{"key":49,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"What was the underworld called by  the Egyptians?","a":"Duat ","b":"Parkilah","c":"Ka","d":"Anubis"},{"key":50,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"What was the jackel headed God of mummification known as?","a":"Thoth","b":"Osiris","c":"Horus","d":"Anubis"},{"key":51,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"What was the 'Leaning Tower of Pisa' originally built as ?","a":"A residential tower","b":"A graveyard","c":"A Cathedral's campanile","d":"A court for the king"},{"key":52,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"Which of the following is a treatise on calligraphy?","a":"Risala -Dar-Khatt-I-tarz-I-Muham","b":"Cilafa-Mir-Jatt-I-farz-I-Akbar","c":"Sarama-Jar-Jisti-Mazi-Qutb","d":"Jurina -Su-Mafi-Calig-Aibak"},{"key":53,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"Which of the following is a former French Enclave?","a":"Yanam","b":"Mahe","c":"Karaikal","d":"Podicherry"},{"key":54,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"What is the early period of Hindi literature known as?","a":"Nathapanthi ","b":"Vajrayana","c":"Rasan","d":"Adikala"},{"key":55,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"Where would one find the Amar Jyoti?","a":"Charminar","b":"Gol Gumbaz","c":"Taj Mahal","d":"India Gate"},{"key":56,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"When did the 1st world war end?","a":"1917","b":"1918","c":"1916","d":"1919"},{"key":57,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"What was the River Amazon called by the Portuguese?","a":"Sarina-da-Juma","b":"Jikava-la","c":"Junido Angelo","d":"O-reo-mac"},{"key":58,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"Into which River did the Pied Piper of Hamlin chase the rats away?","a":"R.Thames","b":"R.Rhine","c":"R.Weezer","d":"R.Nile"},{"key":59,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"Meghalaya was a part of which state before achieving statehood?","a":"Nagaland","b":"Arunachal Pradesh","c":"Manipur","d":"Assam"},{"key":60,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"What is 'Bansuri'also known as?","a":"Murali","b":"Prakash","c":"Ujjal","d":"Raguri"},{"key":61,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"Who is the first person to appear on British stamp other than any royalty?","a":"Alfred Lord Tennyson","b":"Alexander Flemming","c":"William Shakespeare","d":"Robert .E. Peary"},{"key":62,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"Who passed the first budget of free India?","a":"Abu Kalam Azad","b":"Jawaharlal Nehru","c":"R.K.Shanmugam Chettiar","d":"C.Rajagopalachari"},{"key":63,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"Which country adopted its national anthem in 1931, 150 yrs after its independence?","a":"France","b":"USA","c":"Australia","d":"Canada"},{"key":64,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"Which leader was called 'Bismog of India'?","a":"Abu Kalam Azad","b":"C.Rajagopalachari","c":"Sardar Vallabhai Patel","d":"Rajendra Prasad"},{"key":65,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"Who was the first Indian Governer - general of free India?","a":"Dadabhai Nowroji","b":"Gopal Krishna Gokhale","c":"R.K.Shanmugam Chettiar","d":"C.Rajagopalachari"},{"key":66,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"How do we better know Maryada Purushottam?","a":"Rama","b":"Krishna","c":"Bheeshma","d":"Shiva"},{"key":67,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"According to Greek Mythology, who abducted Helen?","a":"Paris","b":"Adis Ababa","c":"Manhattan","d":"Oslo"},{"key":68,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"'Songs of India' is the literary work of which famous leader?","a":"Annie Besant","b":"Madam Cama","c":"Vijayalaskshmi pandit","d":"Sarojini Naidu"},{"key":69,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"What are Homer,Marge and Lisa together known as?","a":"Adam's family","b":"Simpsons","c":"Planet","d":"Parsons"},{"key":70,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"Who wrote the song 'Saare Jahaan se Achcha'?","a":"Ravindranath Tagore","b":"Bankim Chandra Chatterjee","c":"Iqbal","d":"Sarojini Naidu"},{"key":71,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"How do we better know 'Mehrunissa' as?","a":"Cleopatra","b":"Mona Lisa","c":"Mother Teresa","d":"Noorjehan"},{"key":72,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"Which was the first British colony in America?","a":"Boston","b":"Virginia","c":"Michigan","d":"Chicago"},{"key":73,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"The 'Seven years war' was fought between England and which other country?","a":"America","b":"France","c":"Australia","d":"India"},{"key":74,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"Martin Luther king was the professor of which subject in the Wittanberg university?","a":"Theology","b":"Oology","c":"Mycology","d":"Pathology"},{"key":75,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"How many 'Theses' had Martin Luther King published?","a":"95","b":"105","c":"115","d":"125"},{"key":76,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"According to an old Chinese legend who discovered silk?","a":"Msi-Ming-Mi","b":"Gi-Ging -gi","c":"Li-Ling-Lee","d":"Hsi -Ling-Shi"},{"key":77,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"Who wrote 'Indian Philosophy' ?","a":"Dr.S.Radhakirishnan","b":"Dr.Rajendra Prasad","c":"Jawaharlal Nehru","d":"Mahatma Gandhi"},{"key":78,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"Who first treated 'Zero' as a number?","a":"Brahmagupta","b":"Bhaskara","c":"Aristotle","d":"Pythogaras"},{"key":79,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"In which country was the first autographed stamp released?","a":"USA","b":"Britain","c":"India","d":"Russia"},{"key":80,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"What was the 22nd of January,1905 known as?","a":"Black Sunday","b":"Bloody Sunday","c":"White Sunday","d":"Macabee Sunday"},{"key":81,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"Who was the first Indian leader to appear on postage stamps?","a":"Mohandas Karamchand Gandhi","b":"Abu  Kalam Azad","c":"Jawaharlal Nehru","d":"Rajendra Prasad"},{"key":82,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"What was the denomination of the first Indian postage stamp?","a":"Re.1","b":"3 1\/2 Anna","c":"1 Paisa","d":"48 Anna"},{"key":83,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"What is  1 anna equal to ?","a":"0.5 paisa","b":"6 paisa","c":"2 paisa","d":"1\/4 paisa"},{"key":84,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"Who was the first president of Pakistan?","a":"Benazir Bhutto","b":"Suru Kil Iqbal","c":"Iskandar Mirza","d":"Mohammad Ali Jinnah"},{"key":85,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"Which is the largest prison in India?","a":"Tihar jail","b":"Mongol jail","c":"Mandai jail","d":"Andaman jail"},{"key":86,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"Which city was formerly also known as Shahjanabad?","a":"Delhi","b":"Agra","c":"Rajkot","d":"Shimla"},{"key":87,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"3000 yrs before, the Chinese called it the 'Intelligence Park' .What do we now call it?","a":"Museum","b":"Aquarium","c":"Zoo","d":"Garden"},{"key":88,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"Who succeded Lord Dalhousie as Governer General of India ?","a":"Lord Canning","b":"Lord Mountbatten","c":"Lord Curzon","d":"Lord Ripon"},{"key":89,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"Who organised the Vanar - Sena?","a":"Indira Gandhi","b":"Santosh Kumar","c":"Lal Bahadur Shastri","d":"Kamla Nehru"},{"key":90,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"Who was called 'Iron lady of India'?","a":"Rani Lakshmibai","b":"Durgavati","c":"Kasturba Gandhi","d":"Indira Gandhi"},{"key":91,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"What is the India gate also known as?","a":"Amar Bharat Memorial","b":"Bharat Swantantra memorial","c":"All India war memorial","d":"All India Victory memorial"},{"key":92,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"Who was the first Chief election commissioner of free India?","a":"S.P.Sen Verma","b":"Sukumar sen","c":"SL.Shakdhar","d":"R.K.Trivedi"},{"key":93,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"The first assembly elections started on October 1951. When did it end?","a":"November 1951","b":"January 1952","c":"February 1952","d":"December 1951"},{"key":94,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"Who wrote the original version of the Indian constituition 'Bharat Ka Samvidhan'?","a":"M.F.Hussain","b":"Vasantrao Vaidya","c":"Bahadur Sapani","d":"Fali.S.Nariman"},{"key":95,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"What is the Great Indian Peninsula (GIP) railway presently known as?","a":"Western Railway","b":"Perambur Loco","c":"Central Railway","d":"Southern Railway"},{"key":96,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"Who is credited of having performed the opening ceremony of the first railway lines ","a":"Lord Elphinstone","b":"Sir Bartle Frere","c":"GT Clark","d":"Mr.Berkely"},{"key":97,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"What was called a Bakra Gadi?","a":"Bullock carts","b":"A Truck","c":"3rd Class Rly coaches in 1st train of India","d":"The first aeroplane of India"},{"key":98,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"Which engineer studied the possibility of railways between Bombay and Thane?","a":"G.T.Clarke","b":"Mr.Berkely","c":"Sir Bartle Frere","d":"Thomas Nicholas"},{"key":99,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"Who succeeded Lord Wavell as the viceroy?","a":"Lord Mountbatten","b":"Lord Curzon","c":"Lord Pethick Lawrence","d":"Sir Stafford Cripps."},{"key":100,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"What was the middle name of Godse, the man who killed the Mahatma?","a":"Vishnu","b":"Shiva","c":"Vinayak","d":"Murugan"},{"key":101,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"Which agreement was signed between China and India in 1954?","a":"Panchatantra","b":"Panchabhoomi","c":"Pandhagnyan","d":"Panchasheel"},{"key":102,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"When were  the first  general elections held in India?","a":"1952","b":"1951","c":"1950","d":"1957"},{"key":103,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"Mahatma Gandhi organised the Indian ambulance corps for the British in which war of 1899?","a":"Phoenix war","b":"Vol-Krust war","c":"Boer war","d":"Transvaal war"},{"key":104,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"Mahatma Gandhi concluded his 'fast' on Sept 26th ,1932 after the British accepted which pact?","a":"Dandi pact","b":"Yeravada pact","c":"Champaran pact","d":"Young India pact"},{"key":105,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"Which dynasty did Qutbuddin Aibak establish in 1206?","a":"Qutay dynasty","b":"Aybek dynasty","c":"Slave dynasty","d":"Krita dynasty"},{"key":106,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"Whom did the English defeat in the Battle of Buxor?","a":"Siraj-Ud-Daula","b":"Ahmed Shah Abdul","c":"Muhammad Ghazni","d":"Mir Kasim"},{"key":107,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"When was the 'Pitt's India act' passed?","a":"1780","b":"1784","c":"1788","d":"1792"},{"key":108,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"What were the muslims in Malabar known as?","a":"Mafia","b":"Moplah","c":"Kemal","d":"Chaura"},{"key":109,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"To which house did William II Rufus belong?","a":"House of Normandy","b":"House of Plantagnet","c":"House of Lancaster","d":"House of Tudor"},{"key":110,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"Who was the first Chief -Justice to be appointed as the president of India?","a":"V.V.Giri","b":"B.D.Jatti","c":"F.Ali Ahmed","d":"M.Hidayatulla"},{"key":111,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"Mahatma Gandhi was the son of the CM of which princely state in India ?","a":"Gandhinagar","b":"Anandnagar","c":"Porbandar","d":"Vadodara "},{"key":112,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"When was the first meeting of the constituitional assembly held?","a":"27th August 1947","b":"26th January 1950","c":"9th December 1946","d":"7th July 1946"},{"key":113,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"Between which two places were the first railways opened?","a":"Bombay and Thane","b":"Newyork and Seattle","c":"Halifax and Vancour","d":"Stockton and Darlington"},{"key":114,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"Which is the Oldest civilization in the world?","a":"Mesopatian civilization","b":"Nile civilization","c":"Indus civilization","d":"Greek civilization"},{"key":115,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"Who is called the 'Napolean of Eqypt'?","a":"King Tutankhamen","b":"King Luxor-I","c":"Tutmose III","d":"Amon II"},{"key":116,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"According to Egyptian myths, against what would the soul of a dead body be weighed by Anubis?","a":"Feather","b":"Goat","c":"Elephant","d":"Ant"},{"key":117,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"What was the 'Great Pyramid' at Gizeh built of?","a":"Cobalt","b":"Limestone","c":"Basalt","d":"Baked Bricks"},{"key":118,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"What is the Greek term for 'Sacred engraved writing'?","a":"Papyrus","b":"Sheetan","c":"Pulp","d":"Heiroglyphic"},{"key":119,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"Who is known as 'Father of the Gurumukhi Script'?","a":"Amardas","b":"Arjun","c":"Angad","d":"Teg Bahadur"},{"key":120,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"Who founded the Atmiya Sabha in 1815?","a":"Devendra Nath Tagore","b":"M.G.Ranade","c":"Shivnath Shastri","d":"Raja Ram Mohan Roy"},{"key":121,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"Who was the first person to receive the Bharat Ratna posthumously?","a":"Lal Bhahadur Shastri","b":"Gopinath Bardoloi","c":"Acharya Vinoba Bhave","d":"Aruna Asaf Ali"},{"key":122,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"Which was the first organization to receive a Nobel prize?","a":"International Red Cross","b":"Viscount Cecil of Chelwood","c":"Institute of International Law","d":"Amnesty International"},{"key":123,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"Which famous wonder of the world was built during the reign of King Nebuchednezzar?","a":"The colossus of Rhodes","b":"The Hanging gardens","c":"Leaning tower of Pisa","d":"The Stepped Pyramid"},{"key":124,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"What is the sacred book of the Sikhs known as ?","a":"Granth Sahib","b":"Nanak manthra","c":"Michi kami","d":"Angad Sahib"},{"key":125,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"Whom did Mark Chapman assasinate in 1908?","a":"Bismark","b":"Robert Walpole","c":"Archduke Franz Ferdinand","d":"John Lennon"},{"key":126,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"Which famous personality said\" I shall hear in Heaven\"?","a":"Beeth Ovens","b":"Stree Meryl","c":"Sophocles","d":"Charles Percy Snow"},{"key":127,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"Which party did Adolf Hitler begin?","a":"Fascist","b":"Nazi","c":"Semiti","d":"Axis"},{"key":128,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"What is the autobiography of Adolf Hitler known as?","a":"Blitz Kreig","b":"Fume","c":"Mein Kampf","d":"Benito"},{"key":129,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"Which government was called the 'Vishy Government' when it established itself over France?","a":"Russia","b":"England","c":"Austria","d":"Germany"},{"key":130,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"What was the war strategy adopted by Hitler known as?","a":"Geurilla","b":"Blitz krieg","c":"Pethi manuovere","d":"Dunkirk"},{"key":131,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"Which novelist worked as a secretary to the Maharaj of Devas?","a":"Chanakya","b":"Carlos Donald","c":"Edward Morgan Forster","d":"Merta  Samuel"},{"key":132,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"In the Ramayana,who was the wife of  sage Vashista?","a":"Sumitra","b":"Arundati","c":"Subhadra","d":"Urmila"},{"key":133,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"Who called Rabindranath Tagore 'Gurudev'?","a":"Gopal Krishna Gokhale","b":"Dadabhai Nowroji","c":"Vyomesh Chandra Banerjee","d":"Mahatma Gandhi"},{"key":134,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"What is the oldest fossil of prehistoric man called?","a":"Hanupheticus","b":"Nakuphithecus","c":"Sahapithecus","d":"Ramapithecus"},{"key":135,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"What killed Socrates?","a":"Hemlock","b":"Cyanide","c":"Sulphuric acid","d":"Water"},{"key":136,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"How many shlokas does the Ramayana consist of?","a":"19000","b":"24000","c":"39000","d":"27000"},{"key":137,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"What is the sacred book of Confucianism?","a":"Wuching","b":"Ranalum","c":"Jarudi","d":"Fankira"},{"key":138,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"Who wrote the Vande mataram?","a":"Iqpal","b":"Ravindranath Tagore","c":"Bankim Chandra Chatterjee","d":"Dadabhai Nowroji"},{"key":139,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"Who was the first viceroy of India?","a":"Lord Dalhousie","b":"Lord George Canning","c":"Lord Mountbatten","d":"Lord Curzon"},{"key":140,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"Who was the  Governer General when India became Independence?","a":"Lord Mountbatten","b":"Simon Dinons","c":"Rajagopalachari","d":"Gopal Krishna Gokhale"},{"key":141,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"In which country did the Mau-Mau rebellion take place?","a":"China","b":"Japan","c":"Cambodia","d":"Kenya"},{"key":142,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"Which explorer was killed in 1521 , after becoming the first European to sail across the Pacific Ocean?","a":"Marco Polo","b":"Christopher Columbus","c":"Ferdinand Magellan","d":"Vasco-da-gama"},{"key":143,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"Which is the only country in West Africa that was never ruled by an European nation?","a":"Nigeria","b":"Liberia","c":"Sudan","d":"Lesotho"},{"key":144,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"Where would one find the Brindavan Gardens?","a":"Mysore","b":"Bangalore","c":"Kolkata","d":"Delhi"},{"key":145,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"In 1819,Sir Thomas Stanford Raffles established a trading post for the East India company on which island?","a":"Indonesia","b":"Singapore","c":"Srilanka","d":"NewGuinea"},{"key":146,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"Who is the Greek Goddess of Victory?","a":"Nike","b":"Adidas","c":"Bata","d":"Lanacia"},{"key":147,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"Who was the supreme head of The Taliban?","a":"Osama bin laden","b":"Mohammed Sayeed","c":"Bin Ahmed","d":"Mullah Omar"},{"key":148,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"Who was the first woman member of the US congress?","a":"Hillary Clinton","b":"Jeannette Rankin","c":"Mata Hari","d":"Kino Maria"},{"key":149,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"During the epic period it was known as Pragiyotisha. What do we now call it as?","a":"Arunanchal Pradesh","b":"Sikkim","c":"Assam","d":"Meghalaya"},{"key":150,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"With which country would you associate the Red revolution?","a":"China","b":"Japan","c":"Eqypt","d":"Korea"},{"key":151,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"What was the symbol of the Nazi Movement?","a":"Shubhika","b":"Swastika","c":"Utavika","d":"Karmika"},{"key":152,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"In which peace conference was the humiliating 'Treaty of Versailles' signed?","a":"Paris","b":"New York","c":"Shanghai","d":"Berlin"},{"key":153,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"With which nation did the allied powers sign the treaty of St.Germaine?","a":"Hungary","b":"Belgium","c":"Austria","d":"Bulgaria"},{"key":154,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"Which port was given to Poland when it was created ?","a":"Keil","b":"Boston","c":"Alsace","d":"Danzig"},{"key":155,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"Which female revolutionery led the communist party -Spartacist?","a":"Lisitan Maria","b":"Rosa Luxemborg","c":"Julia Kampf","d":"Rhini Mortenson"},{"key":156,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"British PM Winston Churchill and which other political leader declared the Atlantic Manifesto?","a":"Franklin Roosevelt","b":"Woodrow Wilson","c":"Harry Truman","d":"Joseph Stalin"},{"key":157,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"Where was the rough draft of the UN prepared before its formation?","a":"Wimbledon","b":"Geneva","c":"Hall of Mirrors","d":"Dumbarton Oaks"},{"key":158,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"When was Germany divided?","a":"1947","b":"1948","c":"1949","d":"1950"},{"key":159,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"Which Hindu goddess is the personification of the infinite?","a":"Aditi","b":"Lakshmi","c":"Saraswati","d":"Parvati"},{"key":160,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"Who was the last of the Ptolemies, who ruled over Egypt?","a":"Claudius","b":"Latvia","c":"Cleopatra","d":"Lucia"},{"key":161,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"What was the name of the first ever postage stamp ever used?","a":"Sheep Black","b":"Penny Black","c":"Lamb Black","d":"Pound Black"},{"key":162,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"Whom did Akbar defeat in the battle of Haldighat?","a":"Humayun","b":"Hemu","c":"Eslam","d":"Rana pratap"},{"key":163,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"In which battle in 1760 did the English defeat the French?","a":"Wandiwash","b":"Circar","c":"Marquess","d":"Wellesley"},{"key":164,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"Who became the Nawab of Bengal after Siraj-Ud-Daula?","a":"Mir Kasim","b":"Warren Hastings","c":"William Benlinck","d":"Mir Jafer"},{"key":165,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"What was the name of Gandhiji's mother?","a":"Kasturba","b":"Putlibhai","c":"Rani","d":"Viribhai"},{"key":166,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"Who organized the 'Natal Indian Congress'?","a":"Lal Bhahadur Shastri","b":"Jawaharlal Nehru","c":"Mahatma Gandhi","d":"Rajendra Prasad"},{"key":167,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"Who was the viceroy of India before Lord Mountbatten?","a":"Lord Wavell","b":"Lord Dalhousie","c":"Lord Curzon","d":"Lord Canning"},{"key":168,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"When was the Hyderabad state congress established?","a":"1937","b":"1938","c":"1939","d":"1940"},{"key":169,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"Who wrote Arthashastra?","a":"Kanishka","b":"Pushyamitra","c":"Vikramaditya","d":"Khutila"},{"key":170,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"How do we better know Mahesh Das?","a":"Birbal","b":"Tenali Rama","c":"Vikramaditya","d":"Raja Raja Chola"},{"key":171,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"The Lenin shipyard in Gdansk Poland was the nursery of which 20th centurey trade union?","a":"Nafaci","b":"Soliditary","c":"Comonaci","d":"Rambo"},{"key":172,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"Who was the chanceller of Prussia in 1870, when Prussia annexed France?","a":"Bismark","b":"Walpole","c":"Hitler","d":"Mussolini"},{"key":173,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"Who was responsible for the Jalian walabaug Massacre?","a":"Lord Canning","b":"General O Dwyer","c":"Lord Curzon","d":"General Mirkey Fort"},{"key":174,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"Alsace and Lorraine , cities conquered by Germany in 1871 belonged to which country?","a":"Austria","b":"Russia","c":"England","d":"France"},{"key":175,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"What was the atom bomb dropped in Hiroshima named?","a":"Little girl","b":"Little lad","c":"Little boy","d":"Little damsel"},{"key":176,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"Emperor Akbar chose Fatehpur Sikhri as his seat of governance believing it tobe","a":"Mariam Sikhru","b":"Salim Chesti","c":"Sant Ramdas","d":"Sheikh Abdul"},{"key":177,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"Who was the founder of the Mughal empire in India?","a":"Zahiruddin Babur","b":"Sher shah suri","c":"Akbar the Great","d":"Humayun"},{"key":178,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"At which age did Akbar ascend the throne?","a":"18","b":"17","c":"14","d":"13"},{"key":179,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"Which ruler stole the peackock throne in 1739?","a":"Adilshah","b":"Nizam Shah","c":"The British","d":"Nadir Shah"},{"key":180,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"Who was the famous dictator of Italy,who rose to power after WW 1?","a":"General Franco","b":"Adolf Hitler","c":"Benito Mussolini","d":"Premiere Stalin"},{"key":181,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"Who founded the Home Rule League in Maharashtra?","a":"Lokmanya Tilak","b":"Annie Besant","c":"Lala Lajpatirai","d":"Bipin Chandra Pal"},{"key":182,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"Bhagat Singh was hung for the assasination of which British officer?","a":"Jackson","b":"Saunders","c":"Curzon","d":"Nicholas"},{"key":183,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"Who was the first individual satyagrahi?","a":"Mahatma Gandhi","b":"Jawaharlal Nehru","c":"Acharya Vinoba Bhave","d":"Sardar Vallabhai Patel"},{"key":184,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"How many times was Gandhi the congress president?","a":"Once","b":"Twice","c":"Thrice","d":"Never"},{"key":185,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"Who were the first invaders to rule over India ?","a":"Mughal","b":"Maurya","c":"Maratha","d":"Muhammads"},{"key":186,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"On whose gravestone would you find the slogan\"Workers of all lands,White\"?","a":"Mahatma Gandhi","b":"General Franco","c":"Karl Marx","d":"Sophodes"},{"key":187,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"Who started the Bal Hatya Pratibandhak Home?","a":"Swami Dhayanand Saraswati","b":"Keshav Chandra Sen","c":"Gopal Krishna Agarkar","d":"Mahatma Jotirao Phule"},{"key":188,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"Which country of the British empire had been described as the 'Brightest Jewel in the British crown?","a":"Cameroon","b":"Congo","c":"Australia","d":"India"},{"key":189,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"Who was the first President of India to have never been a Vice-President?","a":"Rajendra Prasad","b":"Abdul Kalam","c":"Neelam Sanjeeva Reddy","d":"Giani Zail singh"},{"key":190,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"Which King erected the'Iron Pillar' Known for not rusting for over 1500 years in the courtyard of the Qutb Minar?","a":"Qutbutin Aibak","b":"Vikramaditya","c":"Chandra Verman","d":"Jai Singh"},{"key":191,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"When did our former President Zail singh die?","a":"26th January","b":"25th December","c":"15th August","d":"1st January"},{"key":192,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"Who was the governer of Punjab, when the Jallianwala Baug Massacre occurred?","a":"Micheal O'Dwyer","b":"Gen.R.E.H.Dyer","c":"Lord Curzon","d":"Lord Dalhousie"},{"key":193,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"What was the name of the operation instituted for liberating Hyderabad in 1948?","a":"Operation Vijay","b":"Operation Meghdoot","c":"Operation Polo","d":"Operation Rescue"},{"key":194,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"Which ruler built the 'Qila Rai Pithora' the gates for a defence wall?","a":"Babur","b":"Prithviraj Chauhan III","c":"Ibrahim Lodi","d":"Muhammad Bin Tuglaq"},{"key":195,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"What was Kolkata's original name,when Armenian and Portuguese traders had settled here before the ","a":"Calcutta","b":"Bengal","c":"Kalikata","d":"Cabilcata"},{"key":196,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"How do we better know Bassein?","a":"Vashi","b":"Bandra","c":"Bori Bunder","d":"Vasai"},{"key":197,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"Which British governer built Bombay?","a":"William Emerson","b":"J.L.Kipling","c":"Sir H.B.Edward Frere","d":"Rampart Row"},{"key":198,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"Which year witnessed the out break of the 'American Civil War'?","a":"1929","b":"1861","c":"1857","d":"1807"},{"key":199,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"Which governer defeated Siraj -Ud-Daula in the 'Battle of Plassy' in 1759?","a":"Lord Curzon","b":"Lord Canning","c":"Robert Clive","d":"James Caldwell"},{"key":200,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"Who built the 'Brihadeshwara Temple'?","a":"Varadaraja","b":"Raja Raja Chola","c":"Rajendra Chola","d":"Narasimaverma"},{"key":201,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"In greek mythology, who is the god of war?","a":"Hermes","b":"Apollo","c":"Ares","d":"Zeus"},{"key":202,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"Who was the first victor in the history of olympic games-both ancient and modern?","a":"Elis","b":"Coroebus","c":"Alpheus","d":"Cladeus"},{"key":203,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"Which city was described as 'The Mother of Harlots and Abdomination of the earth?","a":"Elam","b":"Babel","c":"Iraq","d":"Babylon"},{"key":204,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"Which book of ritual and divination was known and respected by Romans in ancient days?","a":"Etrusca Disciplina","b":"Volsinii Bolsena","c":"Tages Piacenza","d":"Etruria Legacyina"},{"key":205,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"Which Olympian wrestler was declared as the descendant of Herculas after he remained","a":"Phidias","b":"Theogenes","c":"Theodosins","d":"Nero"},{"key":206,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"hist","question":"During which chanceller's reign did Germany capture the French provinces oa Alsace & Lorraine in 1871?","a":"Kaiser William","b":"Bismarck","c":"Adolf Hitler","d":"Edward Gibbon"},{"key":207,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"hist","question":"Which treaty was responsible for the second world war?","a":"Treaty of Traunon","b":"Treaty of Severs","c":"Treaty of Laussane","d":"Treaty of Versailles"},{"key":208,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"hist","question":"Who built the 'Chogha Zanbil' in the 13th Century?","a":"Untash Napirisha","b":"Anshan","c":"Inshushinak","d":"Alexander the Great"},{"key":209,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"What was the movement initiated by the leaders of the countries that had attained independence ","a":"Democratic movement","b":"Rights for right movement","c":"Non-Aligned movement","d":"Sovereign nations movement"},{"key":210,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"hist","question":"Sarojini Naidu governed which state from 1947 - 1949?","a":"Maharashtra","b":"Gujarat","c":"Uttar Pradesh","d":"Kerala"},{"key":1,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"general","question":"Which mountaineers hope of conquering all  14 mountains was shattered due to a sneezing fit?","a":"Alan Hinkes","b":"Lala Feru Sherpa","c":"Thomas Drowels","d":"Norida Russell"},{"key":2,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"general","question":"Which was the first Indian motor car?","a":"Hindustan Lobofee","b":"Hindustan 10","c":"Larson Hindustan","d":"Mera Hind"},{"key":3,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"general","question":"What does a bibliosphilist collect?","a":"Bibles","b":"Novels","c":"Torn pages of a Bible","d":"Books"},{"key":4,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"general","question":"TOEFL,TWE, and TSEL are exams to test the proficiency in which lanquage?","a":"English","b":"Economics","c":"Ethology","d":"Theology"},{"key":5,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"general","question":"Who was the 1st person to win the Miss Universe pageant?","a":"Christiane Martel","b":"Carol Morris","c":"Armi Kuusela","d":"Gladys Zender"},{"key":6,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"general","question":"How many years before 2-2-2000 was an all even date recorded?","a":"1002","b":"1112","c":"2223","d":"624"},{"key":7,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"general","question":"Who was the first to win  the Miss World Pageant?","a":"Many Louise Flodin","b":"Marita Lindahl","c":"Denise Perrier","d":"Kerstin Llakonson"},{"key":8,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"general","question":" In which season does the Rathyathra take place?","a":"Sharad Ritu","b":"Shishir Ritu","c":"Hemant Ritu","d":"Greeshma Ritu"},{"key":9,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"general","question":"Where are the engines of a Concorde, the fastest passenger flight , mounted?","a":"On top of the wings","b":"Under the wings","c":"Under the cockpit","d":"Under the 13th seat"},{"key":10,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"general","question":"If an apple grows on an apple tree, what does an Oak tree grow?","a":"oaks","b":"White grape","c":"Acorn","d":"Mini apple"},{"key":11,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"general","question":"Which is the world's second smallest monkey?","a":"Sagui Dwarf","b":"Pygmy Marmoset","c":"Nose Hanger","d":"Varat Elf"},{"key":12,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"general","question":"Who designed the hovercraft?","a":"Leonardo da Vinci","b":"Sir Rene Reaummer","c":"Swan Destin","d":"Sir Christopher Cockerel"},{"key":13,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"general","question":"In the Roman numeral system, what does a number multiply itself with when a dash is shown over","a":"1 lakh","b":"1000","c":"99","d":"999"},{"key":14,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"general","question":"Which is the only vowel used for Roman Numerals?","a":"I","b":"E","c":"O","d":"A"},{"key":15,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"general","question":"How do we better know Steven Kapoor?","a":"Raj Kapoor","b":"Apaache Indian","c":"Nusrat Fateh Ali Khan","d":"A.R.Rahman"},{"key":16,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"general","question":"Which is the most used word or expression in any language of the world?","a":"Hello","b":"Oh!","c":"Ok","d":"Fish!"},{"key":17,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"general","question":"How do we better know David Kotkin?","a":"David Copperfield","b":"Charles Dickens","c":"David Johnson","d":"David Gower"},{"key":18,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"general","question":"What is a pumper nickle?","a":"Bread","b":"Pumpkin","c":"Pickle","d":"Pizza"},{"key":19,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"general","question":"What do you call an auction where prices drop?","a":"slide auction","b":"Fault Auction","c":"Micky mouse auction","d":"Dutch Auction"},{"key":20,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"general","question":"Where would one find the Garba dance?","a":"Rajasthan","b":"Gujarat","c":"Haryana","d":"Punjab"},{"key":21,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"general","question":"When was the Indian national flag planted in the South Pole?","a":"Jan 17","b":"b","c":"1990","d":"Jan 17"},{"key":22,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"general","question":"Which is the smallest and only even prime no?","a":"2","b":"22","c":"14","d":"0"},{"key":23,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"general","question":"Which is the longest key on the key board of a Computer ?","a":"Enter","b":"Delete","c":"Back space","d":"Space bar"},{"key":24,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"general","question":"The queen on a chess board can move like any other coin but one? Which?","a":"Rook","b":"Pawn","c":"Knight","d":"King"},{"key":25,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"general","question":"What does 'M'stand for in HTML?","a":"Monitor","b":"Marker","c":"Minor","d":"Minute"},{"key":26,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"general","question":"What is PhD?","a":"Doctorate of philosophy","b":"Physics of Hydrogen","c":"Penetrated Hydrogen Dioxide","d":"Doctrate of Physics"},{"key":27,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"general","question":"How many directions are marked on a magnetic compass?","a":"4","b":"8","c":"16","d":"32"},{"key":28,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"general","question":"In which state is the Kaziranga sanctuary?","a":"Nagaland","b":"Assam","c":"Mizoram","d":"Meghalaya"},{"key":29,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"general","question":"What is the national anthem of America?","a":"Stars spankled banner","b":"Stripes of victory","c":"Sparkling stars with two","d":"In God we trust"},{"key":30,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"general","question":"Which is the only Zodiac sign without an animal in it?","a":"Capricorn","b":"Virgo","c":"Libra","d":"Aries"},{"key":31,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"general","question":"What does 'Q' stand for in IQ?","a":"Questions","b":"Quotient","c":"Quadrant","d":"Quetty"},{"key":32,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"general","question":"What does the 'M' stand for as in AM and PM?","a":"Moderate","b":"Matric","c":"Median","d":"Meredian"},{"key":33,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"general","question":"What is the name of the first cloned animal?","a":"Cheney","b":"Katty","c":"Dolly","d":"Babe"},{"key":34,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"general","question":"Which festival is also known as 'Yultide'?","a":"Christmas","b":"Easter","c":"Good Friday","d":"Advent week"},{"key":35,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"general","question":"Who was the first pope in the world?","a":"St.Peter","b":"John paul","c":"St.Thomas","d":"Harold Wilson"},{"key":36,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"general","question":"What does 'P' stand for as in POLICE?","a":"Prime","b":"Penance","c":"Protection","d":"Prudent"},{"key":37,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"general","question":"What does 'M' stand for as om CDMA?","a":"Matter","b":"Multiple","c":"Master","d":"Mordent"},{"key":38,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"general","question":"Which company invented the 'Walkman'?","a":"Philips","b":"Sony","c":"Bajaj","d":"LG"},{"key":39,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"general","question":"What does 'T' stand for as in CRT?","a":"Tube","b":"Test","c":"Time","d":"Tapash"},{"key":40,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"general","question":"Which is the smallest natural number?","a":"1","b":"2","c":"0","d":"-1"},{"key":41,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"general","question":"How many make a 'Myriad?","a":"1000","b":"10000","c":"100000","d":"1000000"},{"key":42,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"general","question":"What is the term used for any American President who has lost his re-election bid & is just completing","a":"Jumping Jack","b":"Crawling Duck","c":"Sunk duck","d":"Lame Duck"},{"key":43,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"general","question":"Which is the largest church in the world?","a":"Basilica of Bom Jesus","b":"St.Xaviers church","c":"Basilica of Our lady of peace","d":"St.Johns Church"},{"key":44,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"general","question":"What is the running strip of news at the bottom of a TV screen called?","a":"Roller","b":"Scrawl","c":"Scroll","d":"Athletes"},{"key":45,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"general","question":"What does the 'S'stand for as in 'SUN' of the Sun microsystem?","a":"Stanford","b":"Seargent","c":"Speck","d":"Spark"},{"key":46,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"general","question":"The 3 stars in Iraq's flag represent Eqypt,Syria and\u2026\u2026?","a":"Isreal","b":"Sudan","c":"Iran","d":"Iraq"},{"key":47,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"general","question":"Who is a ' Virtuoso'?","a":"Painter","b":"Carpenter","c":"Musicians","d":"Sportsman"},{"key":48,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"general","question":"Who was the first non - Indian to be awarded the prestigious Bharat Ratna?","a":"Annie Besant","b":"Khan Abdul Gaffar Khan","c":"Madam Cama","d":"A.O.Hume"},{"key":49,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"general","question":"Which is the world's largest painting, though it is no longer remains?","a":"Battle of Gettysburg","b":"MonaLisa","c":"Ornico","d":"Panorama of Missisippi"},{"key":50,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"general","question":"Where is America's Space research centre NASA situated?","a":"Cape Kennady","b":"Cape Daniel","c":"Cape Kingsley","d":"Cape Jerome"},{"key":51,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"general","question":"What does the 'T' stands for as in C-Dot?","a":"Television","b":"Transport","c":"Telematics","d":"Tourisim"},{"key":52,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"general","question":"Where is the National Defence academy situated?","a":"Khadakvasla","b":"New Delhi","c":"Pune","d":"DehraDun"},{"key":53,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"general","question":"Who was known as the 'Lady with the Lamp'?","a":"Kamala Das","b":"Sarojini Naidu","c":"Jhansi Rani","d":"Florence Nightingale"},{"key":54,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"general","question":"What is the process of strengthening rubber known as?","a":"Toughenment","b":"Vulcanization","c":"Fibration","d":"Kakkalization"},{"key":55,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"general","question":"Name the only Indian, to have been the President of the UN General Assembly?","a":"V.K.Krishna Menon","b":"Ravindranath Tagore","c":"Sardar Patel","d":"Vijayalakshmi Pandit"},{"key":56,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"general","question":"What is a man who makes maps known as?","a":"Lexicographer","b":"Copywriter","c":"Cartographer","d":"Geologist"},{"key":57,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"general","question":"What is the Indian Standard Time when the time at Greenwich is 12.00 noon?","a":"5.30 p.m","b":"5.30 a.m","c":"1p.m","d":"1 a.m"},{"key":58,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"general","question":"Where is the HO of the world Health Organization situated?","a":"London","b":"Geneva","c":"New Delhi","d":"New york"},{"key":59,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"general","question":"In which year was decimal coinage introduced in India?","a":"1950","b":"1955","c":"1957","d":"1960"},{"key":60,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"general","question":"What was the State Bank of India formerly known as?","a":"Central Bank of India","b":"Imperial Bank of India","c":"United Bank of India","d":"People's Bank of India"},{"key":61,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"general","question":"What was the Reserve Bank of India formerly known as?","a":"Controlling Bank of India","b":"National Bank Of India","c":"People's Bank of India","d":"Central Bank of India"},{"key":62,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"general","question":"What is the Dove, a symbol of?","a":"Mourning","b":"War","c":"Peace","d":"Faith"},{"key":63,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"general","question":"What is Adolf Hitler known as?","a":"Feuhrer","b":"Little Corporal","c":"Man of Iron","d":"Smotherer"},{"key":64,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"general","question":"What is Red Triangle a symbol of?","a":"Family planning","b":"Red Cross","c":"Stop signal","d":"Blue Cross"},{"key":65,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"general","question":"Who was the first Asian to win a Noble prize?","a":"Vladimir Nakov","b":"C.V.Raman","c":"R.N.Tagore","d":"Gorbachev"},{"key":66,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"general","question":"What is the result obtained by calculating the ratio of a person's mental age to his physical age, known as?","a":"GK","b":"C.Dot","c":"IQ","d":"G-mat"},{"key":67,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"general","question":"Which airline , in 1962, became the first all jet airline?","a":"Lufthansa","b":"Air India","c":"Aeroline Aerofloat","d":"American Airlines"},{"key":68,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"general","question":"Which state housed the first Ramyana Art Museum?","a":"Madhya Pradesh","b":"Rajasthan","c":"Kerala","d":"Gujarat"},{"key":69,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"general","question":"Which city was India's summer capital from 1864 to 1941?","a":"Bombay","b":"Calcutta","c":"Shimla","d":"Darjeeling"},{"key":70,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"general","question":"What was the Eden Garden earlier known as?","a":"Connaught Circus","b":"Fanny Circus","c":"Emily Circus","d":"Auckland Circus"},{"key":71,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"general","question":"Who is known as the 'Father of Greek Tragedy'?","a":"Aeschylus","b":"Aristophanes","c":"Izaak Walton","d":"Allen Lane"},{"key":72,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"general","question":"Who is known as the 'Father of Railways'?","a":"Adam Smith","b":"George Stephenson","c":"Robert Boyle","d":"John Bell"},{"key":73,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"general","question":"What is Benito Mussolini also known as ?","a":"Fuhrer","b":"Il Duce","c":"Mahanama","d":"Desert Fox"},{"key":74,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"general","question":"Who is also known as 'Board of Avon'?","a":"Alfred.L.Tennyson","b":"C.F.Andrew","c":"William Shakespeare","d":"George Washington"},{"key":75,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"general","question":"What is the fear of money known as?","a":"Chrometophobia","b":"Cibophobia","c":"Claustrophobia","d":"Cryophobia"},{"key":76,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"general","question":"Who is known as the 'Father of Comedy'?","a":"Charlie Chaplin","b":"Aristophanes","c":"Robert Williams","d":"William Caxton"},{"key":77,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"general","question":"What was Malawi previously known as?","a":"Basutoland","b":"Volgograd","c":"Nyasaland","d":"Greenland"},{"key":78,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"general","question":"Which day is observed as NRI day?","a":"2009-01-01 00:00:00","b":"2010-01-01 00:00:00","c":"2012-01-01 00:00:00","d":"2015-01-01 00:00:00"},{"key":79,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"general","question":"Which country is known as 'Emerald Island'?","a":"Eqypt","b":"Ireland","c":"Greenland","d":"Switzerland"},{"key":80,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"general","question":"Which country is known as 'Land of Cakes'?","a":"Trinidad","b":"Bahrain","c":"Gibraltar","d":"Scotland"},{"key":1,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"religions","question":"What is the name of the Prophet of Zoroastrianism?","a":"Zarathustra","b":"Ahura Mazda","c":"Hermuzd","d":"Baman"},{"key":2,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"religions","question":"When is the Parsee New year celebrated?","a":"April","b":"May","c":"December","d":"August"},{"key":3,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"religions","question":"From where did the Parsees come to India?","a":"Turkey","b":"Iran","c":"Iraq","d":"Kuwait"},{"key":4,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"religions","question":"What do the Parsees  worship?","a":"Water","b":"Wind","c":"Fire","d":"Mountains"},{"key":5,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"religions","question":"Why do the parsees  worship fire?","a":"Fire is the purest of all elements","b":"No one can touch the fire","c":"Fire can destroy their enemies","d":"Fire is easily available to worship"},{"key":6,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"religions","question":"What is the thread ceremony of the Parsees called?","a":"Ijasne","b":"Navjote","c":"Ajargan","d":"Baj"},{"key":7,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"religions","question":"When does a child become a Zoroastrian?","a":"After the Navjote ceremony is done","b":"While the child enters the fire temple","c":"After the child see the holy fire","d":"When the child learns about Zoroastrianism"},{"key":8,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"religions","question":"Where do the Zoroastrians pray?","a":"In the fire temple \/ agiary","b":"In the fire mosque","c":"In the fire church","d":"In a big ground"},{"key":9,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"religions","question":"Where did the Zoroastrians first land in India?","a":"Panjim in Goa","b":"At Sanjan in Gujarat","c":"Bhuj in Gujarat","d":"Mumbai in Maharashtra"},{"key":10,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"religions","question":"How old is Zoroastrianism?","a":"3000 yrs old","b":"1000 yrs old","c":"5000 yrs old","d":"2000 yrs old"},{"key":11,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"religions","question":"Who were Zarathustra's parents?","a":"Havai & Mehermosh","b":"Hutoxi & Ardeshir","c":"Banoo& Yazad","d":"Dagdo & Pourushasp"},{"key":12,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"religions","question":"Where is the holy place of worship for the Parsee community  in India?","a":"Udwada","b":"Koliwada","c":"Baroda","d":"Vijayawada"},{"key":13,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"religions","question":"What is the name of the god of Zoroastrians?","a":"Lohrasp","b":"Ahura Mazda","c":"Peshotan","d":"Rustom"},{"key":14,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"religions","question":"What was the occupation of Joseph, father of Jesus Christ?","a":"Mason","b":"Carpenter","c":"Shepherd","d":"Cobbler"},{"key":15,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"religions","question":"According to the Bible, who lived for the most no of years?","a":"Inoch","b":"Moses","c":"Noah","d":"Methuselah"},{"key":16,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"religions","question":"How many days did it rain when God send the great flood,during the time of Noah as mentioned in the Bible?","a":"40 days","b":"7 days","c":"33 days","d":"25 days"},{"key":17,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"religions","question":"How many years did Jesus Christ live on earth?","a":"69 yrs","b":"53 yrs","c":"33 yrs","d":"40 yrs"},{"key":18,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"religions","question":"Where was Jesus Christ crucified?","a":"Mount of Zion","b":"Ararat","c":"Golgotha","d":"Sinai"},{"key":19,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"religions","question":"Where did Noah's ark rest after the flood?","a":"Himalaya","b":"Alps","c":"Mount of Zion","d":"Ararat"},{"key":20,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"religions","question":"According to the Bible, who was the first child born from the mother's womb?","a":"Cain","b":"Abel","c":"Seth","d":"Enoch"},{"key":21,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"religions","question":"Who baptized Jesus Christ?","a":"Mark","b":"St.John","c":"Matthew","d":"John the Baptist"},{"key":22,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"religions","question":"People belonging to which congregation were first called Christians?","a":"Antioch","b":"Rome","c":"Bethlehem","d":"Jeruasalem"},{"key":23,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"religions","question":"Which was the first miracle performed by Jesus Christ?","a":"the resurrection of Lazarus from death","b":"Curing the blind","c":"Curing the leppers","d":"Changing water into wine"},{"key":24,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"religions","question":"How many silver coins were offered to Judas Iscariot to reveal the identity of Jesus Christ to  his enemies?","a":"30 coins","b":"50 coins","c":"25 coins","d":"75 coins"},{"key":25,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"religions","question":"Which son of Ravana was killed by Hanuman when he first visited Srilanka?","a":"Sundaram","b":"Akshaya","c":"Dhritishtra","d":"Duryodhana"},{"key":26,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"religions","question":"What is a Greek God said to be?","a":"Relegious Traveller","b":"Beautiful bird","c":"Ugly duckling","d":"Handsome man"},{"key":27,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"religions","question":"Who is called Dharmaputra in the Mahabharata?","a":"Krishna","b":"Rama","c":"Yudhishtra","d":"Dhritishtra"},{"key":28,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"religions","question":"Which is the longest epic ever written?       ","a":"Ramayana","b":"Odyssey","c":"Iliad","d":"Mahabharata"},{"key":29,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"religions","question":"In Greek Mythology, who among the following is considered to be a monster?","a":"Hydra","b":"Aurelia","c":"Ardy","d":"Jupiter"},{"key":30,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"religions","question":"In Ramayana, which part of Shoorpanaka was cut off?","a":"Toe","b":"Nose","c":"Finger","d":"Ear"},{"key":31,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"religions","question":"Which animal is Hydra, the Greek monster?","a":"Dinosaur","b":"Snake","c":"Dragon","d":"Elephant"},{"key":32,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"religions","question":"In which Kanda, in Ramayana does Hanuman meet Rama?","a":"Sundara Kanda","b":"Kishkinda Kanda","c":"Shiragu Kanda","d":"Bala kanda"},{"key":33,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"religions","question":"Who presented Arjuna, his celestial bow, Gandeeva?","a":"Vaayu","b":"Jal","c":"Aakash","d":"Agni"},{"key":34,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"religions","question":"Which of the following is the name for a Greek sun God?","a":"Hydra","b":"Zeus","c":"Jupiter","d":"Khnum"},{"key":35,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"religions","question":"Who is Lord Jagannath's sister?","a":"Sumitra","b":"Somoa","c":"Subhadra","d":"Paryush"},{"key":36,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"religions","question":"Sitting in the cave of which mountain did prophet Mohammad meet Gabriel?","a":"Mt.Hira","b":"Mt.Daulat","c":"Mt.Dhan","d":"Mt.Fitr"},{"key":37,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"religions","question":"In the Mahabharata,what is Devarata better known as?","a":"Bheeshma","b":"Yudishtra","c":"Karna","d":"Krishna"},{"key":38,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"religions","question":"Pasupata' was the weapon of which God?","a":"Krishna","b":"Shiva","c":"Vishnu","d":"Brahma"},{"key":39,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"religions","question":"Who is the Roman god of youth?","a":"Juventus","b":"Athena","c":"Hera","d":"Apollo"},{"key":40,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"religions","question":"Who is the Roman messenger of Gods?","a":"Venus","b":"Mercury","c":"Jupiter","d":"Saturn"},{"key":41,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"religions","question":"According to Hindu Mythology who is the God of wealth?","a":"Kuberan","b":"Saraswati","c":"Kumba","d":"Lakshmi"},{"key":42,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"religions","question":"According to Greek myths,which handsome youth fell in love with his own reflection in the pool?","a":"Narcissus","b":"Cupid","c":"Ulysses","d":"Calipso"},{"key":43,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"religions","question":"Who was the first commander in chief of the Mahabharata war?","a":"Krishna","b":"Arjuna","c":"Bheeshma","d":"Karna"},{"key":44,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"religions","question":"Where was Jesus Christ Born?","a":"His House","b":"A Manger","c":"An Inn","d":"A Synagogue"},{"key":45,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"religions","question":"Who was the Charioteer of Dhritarashtra?","a":"Akshaya","b":"Sanjaya","c":"Jhamu","d":"Swamya"},{"key":46,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"religions","question":"Which greek hero was promised immortality by Calipso, if he stayed forever in her island?","a":"Narcissus","b":"Cupid","c":"Ulysses","d":"Ontario"},{"key":47,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"religions","question":"In the Ramayana,who was known to be well versed in music?","a":"Hanuman","b":"Ravana","c":"Krishna","d":"Rama"},{"key":48,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"religions","question":"Who is the Roman God of Love?","a":"Cupid","b":"Jupiter","c":"Mercury","d":"Earth"},{"key":49,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"religions","question":"Whom did the  sumerians believe to be their sun god?","a":"Shamash","b":"Enlil","c":"Isther","d":"Nergal"},{"key":50,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"religions","question":"Which God is said to be holding a thunderbolt in his hand?","a":"Allah","b":"b","c":"c","d":"d"},{"key":51,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"religions","question":"In Greek mythology, what was the food of the gods called?","a":"Courtneisia","b":"Vivisia","c":"Ambrosia","d":"Dillosia"},{"key":52,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"religions","question":"Which character appears both in Ramayana & Maharahstra?","a":"Hanuman","b":"Bheeshma","c":"Krishna","d":"Rama"},{"key":53,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"religions","question":"Which mountain appears both in Mahabharata and Ramayana?","a":"Sanjeeva","b":"Govardhana","c":"Kashinuttur","d":"Karata"},{"key":54,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"religions","question":"With which religion would you associate Mahavir Jayanti?","a":"Buddhism","b":"Sikhism","c":"Anglicaism","d":"Jainism"},{"key":55,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"religions","question":"Which stories tell the tales of Buddha's previous births?","a":"Jataka tales","b":"Panchatantra","c":"Vishu vara","d":"Sainik"},{"key":56,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"religions","question":"Which disciple of Jesus hung himself after betraying Jesus Christ?","a":"Matthew","b":"Peter","c":"Judas Iscariot","d":"Bartholomew"},{"key":57,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"religions","question":"In which city was Jesus born?","a":"Bethlehem","b":"Jerusalem","c":"Ramah","d":"Jericho"},{"key":58,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"religions","question":"According to Hindu mythology,when did the 'Kalyuga' begin?","a":"1914AD","b":"Christian Era","c":"4 BC","d":"3102 BC"},{"key":59,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"religions","question":"How many days are there in a year, according to the Hindu calender?","a":"365","b":"360","c":"355","d":"350"},{"key":60,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"religions","question":"Which sacred book means 'Songs of God'?","a":"Bible","b":"Granth sahib","c":"Bhagwatgita","d":"Quran"},{"key":61,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"religions","question":"On which mountain is Lord Shiva portrayed as the 'Great Yogi'?","a":"Himalayas","b":"Kailasa","c":"Rameshwaram","d":"Nilgiri"},{"key":62,"correct_answer":"a","subject":"religions","question":"What is the name of Shakti, Lord Shiva's spouse , in her benefecient form?","a":"Parvati","b":"Rekha","c":"Parashakti","d":"Durga"},{"key":63,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"religions","question":"Who is Lord Vishnu's wife?","a":"Radha","b":"Rekha","c":"Lakshmi","d":"Durga"},{"key":64,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"religions","question":"Buddha's father, Shuddanona was a \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026?","a":"Potter","b":"Peasant","c":"Accountant","d":"King"},{"key":65,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"religions","question":"What does 'Mahayana' means?","a":"Little Vehicle","b":"Conqueror","c":"Large Vehicle","d":"Doctrine of elders"},{"key":66,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"religions","question":"According to Hindu mythology, which Goddess chose Kerala, when granted a choice to select a land to reside?","a":"Parvati","b":"Kali","c":"Darikan","d":"Lakshmi"},{"key":67,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"religions","question":"Lord Jaganath is an incarnation of which God?","a":"Shiva","b":"Vishnu","c":"Krishna","d":"Brahma"},{"key":68,"correct_answer":"c","subject":"religions","question":"According to the Bible, which is the oldest city?","a":"Jerusalem","b":"Nazareth","c":"Jericho","d":"Cairo"},{"key":69,"correct_answer":"d","subject":"religions","question":"What are the 24 Jains said to have attained?","a":"Mahayana","b":"Hinayana","c":"Bodhisattva","d":"Kaivalya"},{"key":70,"correct_answer":"b","subject":"religions","question":"In the Ramayana, which relative of Ravan always kept sleeping?","a":"Vibushan","b":"Kumbakarna","c":"Indrajeet","d":"Maricha"}]